<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2014 on Steve Hemingway&#39;s website</title>
    <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2014/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2014 on Steve Hemingway&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>(c) Steve Hemingway 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 15:36:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stevehemingway.com/2014/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>December Article</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2014/december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 15:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2014/december/</guid>
      <description>NHDC Waste Collection  David Percival in last month&amp;rsquo;s Parish News commented: &amp;ldquo;contracted refuse collectors routinely dump emptied wheelie bins at random on pavements all around our village&amp;rdquo;. I contacted the officer at NHDC responsible for the waste and recycling contract with Veolia and this is what she wrote about the contract:
&amp;ldquo;The operatives should be placing any bins or boxes back where they came from. They, in particular, should not be leaving them obstructing driveways or footpaths unnecessarily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November Article</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2014/november/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 15:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2014/november/</guid>
      <description>Application to redevelop the GP Surgery at 1 Stevenage Road The future of Knebworth and Marymead GP Practice at 1 London Road has been uncertain for a considerable time. Various proposals for it moving have been discussed without any coming close to fruition. A number of residents were surprised to read about an application to redevelop the surgery into eight one-bedroom flats, submitted by the owner of the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October Article</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2014/october/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 15:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2014/october/</guid>
      <description>Planning Matters Several significant applications are due to be considered by the KPC Planning Committee on 13th October. Please submit your comments to NHDC before the deadline if you have views, and/or raise them with the KPC Planning Committee. As in all Parish and District Council meetings, members of the public are welcome to attend committee meetings:
Knebworth GP Surgery: An application has been made for 1 Stevenage Road a proposal for eight one-bedroom flats on the site of the Knebworth GP Surgery – the deadline for comments to be made to NHDC is 9th October, and as HCC is responsible for the provision of the GP surgeries, Knebworth’s HCC representative, Cllr Richard Thake, is fully involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knebworth Parish News, Sept 2014</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2014/september/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2014/september/</guid>
      <description>Swangley&amp;rsquo;s Farm Solar PV As you may already be aware, there is a proposal to build a &amp;lsquo;solar farm&amp;rsquo; on one of the fields comprising Swangley&amp;rsquo;s Farm. This will involve covering much of the field with solar panels, fixed on metal frames, installing a container-sized inverter building, and connecting the latter to the grid. The field is at the junction of Swangley&amp;rsquo;s Lane and Baines Lane, at the eastern boundary of the parish, where it borders Datchworth Parish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2014/august/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 15:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2014/august/</guid>
      <description>Letchworth Update The work of the council does not stop over the summer, although it does slow down a bit. I have now attended sessions of each of the committees on which I sit: Southern Rural, Overview and Scrutiny, as well the first meeting of the full council in this, its fortieth year civic year. I have also undertaken various sessions of training and induction, and am now inducted into the mysteries of everything from governance, to planning to IT.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>