<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Steve Hemingway&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://stevehemingway.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Steve Hemingway&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>(c) Steve Hemingway 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 15:36:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://stevehemingway.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Redevelopment of Chas Lowe Site</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/chas_lowe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 15:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/chas_lowe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may be aware, Chas Lowes site has been sold and the shop will be closing at the end of this month.  Mccarthy and Stone have purchased the site and will be giving an open presentation of their &amp;lsquo;proposes Plan&amp;rsquo; on the 28th of March in Trinity Church between noon and 7:30pm.
If you have views on how you would like to see the site developed, please do attend.
The presentation is being made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://remarkablegroup.co.uk/&#34;&gt;The Remarkable Group&lt;/a&gt; who are handling the PR for McCarthy and Stone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Steve Hemingway</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 16:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-this-website&#34;&gt;About this website&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my latest corner of the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to have a blog at Tumblr. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://stevehemingway.tumblr.com/&#34;&gt;old posts&lt;/a&gt; are still there, but I won&amp;rsquo;t be adding to them. I generally don&amp;rsquo;t see promoted posts in my browser, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware that my genuine posts were interspersed with promoted ones suggesting that people should check to see if they were due mis-sold PPI and the like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a price which is too much, especially as there are many free alternatives. I am hosting this both on my own mail server on digital ocean and on github pages, which is entirely free. I probably will drop the github pages hosting once I get comfortable with the Digital Ocean offering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have various social media accounts. I&amp;rsquo;ll sort out some links to them eventually.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on Blog Setup</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/update_on_blog_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 15:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/update_on_blog_setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Git submodules are still a bit of a mystery to me, but I yet again followed the instructions on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; and this time it kind of worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It finally dawned on me that git push and pull link a local work tree to a remote repository. You can&amp;rsquo;t run a web server on the remote machine, point it at the repository, and expect it to serve web pages, even though that&amp;rsquo;s what the repository (possibly) contains. Git gurus, stop rolling your eyes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t even checkout the repository on the local machine because then git push will complain that you&amp;rsquo;re pushing to a master branch that it active and checked out on the remote machine. I discovered that the hard way. My web server does run a git server process. I tried it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, after a bit of faffing around (!) I decided to edit the hugo source web file source on my local machine (running msys2 under Windows), push to github.com (because it is so awesome as a git server, and its free), then git pull the (built) website source from github to my web server directory on my dreamhost shared web server machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to add to my blog I create a markdown file, add it to the github pages repo, then git pull it to the dreamhost machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a slight added complication, I run the DNS for this domain on another machine - a digital ocean dropbox, running mail-in-a-box. I discover I have to look in the dreamhost control panel DNS settings for the domain to see what IP address to use for the A record. I can&amp;rsquo;t just use the main (arago) IP address. This is not entirely straightforward. I had to setup a number of A records: the blog.stevehemingway record and the bare record (@), to different IP addresses. The DNS section of the domain management part the Dreamhost control panel gives the list of DNS records to set up. Having the mail server running on a completely different platform is not a problem: to keep this working, all that is needed is a good set of MX records, which Mail-in-a-box sets up automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the sort of thing that makes setting up a website so much messier than it should be, and is the reason that firms like Squarespace will thrive, as they offer a complete, bundled solution for a fixed, modest monthly fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who would have thought that something so simple could be so &amp;hellip;. messy?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/March_Newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 22:57:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/March_Newsletter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NORTH HERTFORDSHIRE DISTRICT COUNCIL – MARCH UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the penultimate meeting of NHDC for the current civic year, the budget for &lt;sup&gt;2017&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;18&lt;/sub&gt; was agreed.  Further savings were identified, as well as a substantial programme of capital expenditure. The council faces challenging times ahead as it has to contend with dwindling revenues from the New Homes Bonus and from Business Rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The council&amp;rsquo;s focus is on making North Herts, in all its diversity, a better place for and working.  It aims to do this by working with partners to provide &amp;lsquo;an attractive and safe environment for our residents&amp;rsquo;. Currently, we are working towards a joint waste collection contract with East Herts District Council. Waste collection is not the most glamorous of activities, but it is the biggest item in the expenditure budget, accounting for 45% of the total!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The council has an objective &amp;lsquo; To promote sustainable growth within our district to ensure economic and social opportunities exist for our communities&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo;. The main driver of this is the Local Plan. It also includes a £1m Capital Enhancement Fund, for community halls throughout the District, to be delivered over the next four years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third and final objective is to &amp;lsquo;deliver cost effective and necessary services to our residents&amp;rsquo;.  Where these services are charged for at the point of use, such as for planning applications, the fees are also prescribed centrally. However, the council does operate a very successful Careline service. This award-winning service helps elderly and infirm residents to continue living at home. NHDC is also about to launch a building regulations inspection service and hopes that this will be a source of income. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, NHDC does not have a free hand in most of the services it provides. They are so-called &amp;lsquo;statutory services&amp;rsquo;, prescribed by the national government. In most cases these are free, for example waste collection. Where charges can be made (e.g. planning applications), the rates are set nationally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the more controversial policies recently has been the one which applies to community halls owned by the council. The policy has been to lease these to local groups on a &amp;lsquo;repairing and insuring lease&amp;rsquo;. This has put some pressure on some local groups who find that it is difficult to adapt to paying for the costs of maintaining their premises. It does, however, put them on an equal footing with groups in parished areas, like Knebworth. Parishes, such as ours, have always had to bear these costs, especially now capital grants for village halls have largely dried up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, by now you&amp;rsquo;re probably wondering how much your council tax is going to go up in April. The NHDC precept for a Band D property will be £216.96 next year, an increase of £5, an increase of 2.4% in cash terms, close to zero in real terms. Not great, but as low as was reasonably achieveable in the circumstances.  (The rest of your Council Tax is made up of contributions to the County Council, the Police and the Parish Council.) For other Council Tax Bands, see the NHDC website, or just wait for your bill to be delivered.&lt;span id=&#34;header-c48&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Station Pub</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/StationPub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 14:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/StationPub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My experience of the Station Pub in Knebworth is not one that makes me want to go back. The pub is cold, noisy and rarely populated by anyone I know. This is a pity, as it&amp;rsquo;s a very short distance from where I live. A few months ago, word went out that it had been advertised for sale. There were a few discussions about it in the Parish Council, where we decided that we&amp;rsquo;d better apply for it to be listed as an asset of community value. Planning applications to develop a very high density development of flats have been received for the site across the road, which have so far been refused, but eventually will result in some residential development happening. In spite of the fact that this is not something that anyone who lives in the village want to see built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, heard that the pub had closed its doors, and the staff had been redeployed in other Greene King pubs nearby. A flurry of activity happened, which resulted in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a new Twitter account was set up to tweet the latest news about the pub,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a new Facebook being set up that rapidly went from zero to around 600 members by the end of the weekend,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a new website being created, which has received hundreds of hits,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a mailing list being set up to collect pledges and offers to help with a campaign.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the website &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stationpub.org.uk&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, where you&amp;rsquo;ll find links to all the aspects of the campaign&amp;rsquo;s web presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is quite astonishing is how rapidly the residents of Knebworth could be alerted to the closing of the pub and the existence of a campaign to save it. I have always been an advocate of local politicians using social media, usually in the face of extreme skepticism from the assembled company. Although I&amp;rsquo;d like to think that this example would persuade them of the effectiveness of the web, my experience is that people can be very obdurate in their views.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community engagement using Facebook</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/facebook_activism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 15:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/facebook_activism/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-station-pub-knebworth&#34;&gt;The Station Pub, Knebworth&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was contacted yesterday, in my capacity as ward councillor, about the closure of the Station Pub.
This is the only pub in the village, and, since it is right in the centre, was very visible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommended creating a Facebook Group. I had a meeting, and someone else set up the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I found that hundreds had already joined, and a further three hundred were queing up to join today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rate of joining this group was astonishing. I am now convinced that mailing lists are comprehensively obsoleted by Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people do not use FB, but the ease of adding someone to a group is so great that there is no other medium that can work so quickly. The problem is that this only works when the campaign is something that people are seriously affected by, or at least interested in. A cause that nobody cares about much will go nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Twitter the key Social Media Platform?</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/Twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/Twitter/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-experience-of-the-twittersphere&#34;&gt;My experience of the Twittersphere&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been on Twitter for a long time. Since 2007. From a time before Stephen Fry discovered the medium, and many years before Donald Trump did so. I&amp;rsquo;ve mainly used it passively. I kept my account private, and followed only those authors whose work interested me. A lot of libertarian comment and analysis, some humour, especially the dark side. I have a number of followers, but get virtually no engagement with them. They are either people I follow, and feel that it is only good manners to follow back, or people who somehow have the email address linked to the account in the address book they have handed over to Twitter Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I have never tweeted anything very incendiary, and do not follow anyone I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want my mother to know I was following, I decided that when I was elected I&amp;rsquo;d better start a new account for the political me. This happened in 2014, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been quietly tweeting since, without much traction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of late I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to integrate a bit more automation, using ifttt.com, and simply linking my Twitter account to a FB page. I&amp;rsquo;d previously auto tweeted from my Tumblr blog, but that never seemed to do any good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, for reasons quite beyond me, my follower numbers seem to be accelerating. The threat to close the Station Pub seems a catalyst. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just that my odd retweet is enough to create a sustaining wave. I confess to paying a magnificent £10 to promote one tweet, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing that again in a hurry, as there seems to be no way to localize the audience, in contrast to FB.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post with a Background Image</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/techie_stuff/background-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/techie_stuff/background-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here be a sample post with a custom background image. To utilize this &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; just add the following YAML to a post&amp;rsquo;s front matter.&lt;/p&gt;
background: /images/filename.png

&lt;p&gt;This little bit of YAML makes the assumption that your background image asset is in the &lt;code&gt;/images&lt;/code&gt; folder. If you place it somewhere else or are hotlinking from the web, just include the full http(s):// URL. Either way you should have a background image that is tiled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to set a background image for the entire site just add &lt;code&gt;background: /images/filename.png&lt;/code&gt; as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/overview/configuration/#examples&#34;&gt;param&lt;/a&gt; in your config and BOOM &amp;mdash; background images on every page!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; xmlns:dct=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/terms/&#34; about=&#34;http://subtlepatterns.com&#34; class=&#34;notice&#34;&gt;Background images from &lt;span property=&#34;dct:title&#34;&gt;Subtle Patterns&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; href=&#34;http://subtlepatterns.com&#34;&gt;Subtle Patterns&lt;/a&gt;) / &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA 3.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntax Highlighting Post</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/techie_stuff/code-highlighting-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/techie_stuff/code-highlighting-post/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Syntax highlighting is a feature that displays source code, in different colors and fonts according to the category of terms. This feature facilitates writing in a structured language such as a programming language or a markup language as both structures and syntax errors are visually distinct. Highlighting does not affect the meaning of the text itself; it is intended only for human readers.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;highlighted-code-blocks&#34;&gt;Highlighted Code Blocks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To modify styling and highlight colors edit &lt;code&gt;/static/css/_sass/_syntax.scss&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
#container {
    float: left;
    margin: 0 -240px 0 0;
    width: 100%;
}
&lt;nav class=&#34;pagination&#34; role=&#34;navigation&#34;&gt;
    {% if page.previous %}
        &lt;a href=&#34;{{ site.url }}{{ page.previous.url }}&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; title=&#34;{{ page.previous.title }}&#34;&gt;Previous article&lt;/a&gt;
    {% endif %}
    {% if page.next %}
        &lt;a href=&#34;{{ site.url }}{{ page.next.url }}&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; title=&#34;{{ page.next.title }}&#34;&gt;Next article&lt;/a&gt;
    {% endif %}
&lt;/nav&gt;&lt;!-- /.pagination --&gt;
module Jekyll
  class TagIndex &lt; Page
    def initialize(site, base, dir, tag)
      @site = site
      @base = base
      @dir = dir
      @name = &#39;index.html&#39;
      self.process(@name)
      self.read_yaml(File.join(base, &#39;_layouts&#39;), &#39;tag_index.html&#39;)
      self.data[&#39;tag&#39;] = tag
      tag_title_prefix = site.config[&#39;tag_title_prefix&#39;] || &#39;Tagged: &#39;
      tag_title_suffix = site.config[&#39;tag_title_suffix&#39;] || &#39;–&#39;
      self.data[&#39;title&#39;] = &#34;#{tag_title_prefix}#{tag}&#34;
      self.data[&#39;description&#39;] = &#34;An archive of posts tagged #{tag}.&#34;
    end
  end
end

&lt;h3 id=&#34;standard-code-block&#34;&gt;Standard Code Block&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;nav class=&amp;quot;pagination&amp;quot; role=&amp;quot;navigation&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    {% if page.previous %}
        &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;{{ site.url }}{{ page.previous.url }}&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;btn&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;{{ page.previous.title }}&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Previous article&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
    {% endif %}
    {% if page.next %}
        &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;{{ site.url }}{{ page.next.url }}&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;btn&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;{{ page.next.title }}&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Next article&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
    {% endif %}
&amp;lt;/nav&amp;gt;&amp;lt;!-- /.pagination --&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fenced-code-blocks&#34;&gt;Fenced Code Blocks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To modify styling and highlight colors edit &lt;code&gt;/static/css/_sass/_coderay.scss&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
#container {
    float: left;
    margin: 0 -240px 0 0;
    width: 100%;
}
&lt;nav class=&#34;pagination&#34; role=&#34;navigation&#34;&gt;
    {% if page.previous %}
        &lt;a href=&#34;{{ site.url }}{{ page.previous.url }}&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; title=&#34;{{ page.previous.title }}&#34;&gt;Previous article&lt;/a&gt;
    {% endif %}
    {% if page.next %}
        &lt;a href=&#34;{{ site.url }}{{ page.next.url }}&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34; title=&#34;{{ page.next.title }}&#34;&gt;Next article&lt;/a&gt;
    {% endif %}
&lt;/nav&gt;&lt;!-- /.pagination --&gt;
module Jekyll
  class TagIndex &lt; Page
    def initialize(site, base, dir, tag)
      @site = site
      @base = base
      @dir = dir
      @name = &#39;index.html&#39;
      self.process(@name)
      self.read_yaml(File.join(base, &#39;_layouts&#39;), &#39;tag_index.html&#39;)
      self.data[&#39;tag&#39;] = tag
      tag_title_prefix = site.config[&#39;tag_title_prefix&#39;] || &#39;Tagged: &#39;
      tag_title_suffix = site.config[&#39;tag_title_suffix&#39;] || &#39;–&#39;
      self.data[&#39;title&#39;] = &#34;#{tag_title_prefix}#{tag}&#34;
      self.data[&#39;description&#39;] = &#34;An archive of posts tagged #{tag}.&#34;
    end
  end
end

&lt;h3 id=&#34;github-gist-embed&#34;&gt;GitHub Gist Embed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of a Gist embed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/mmistakes/43a355923921d22cd993.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syntax_highlighting&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syntax_highlighting&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample Link Post</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/techie_stuff/sample-link-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/techie_stuff/sample-link-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This theme supports &lt;strong&gt;link posts&lt;/strong&gt;, made famous by John Gruber. To use, just add &lt;code&gt;link: http://url-you-want-linked&lt;/code&gt; to the post&amp;rsquo;s YAML front matter and you&amp;rsquo;re done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Post with a Video</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/techie_stuff/video-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/techie_stuff/video-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/SU3kYxJmWuQ&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video embeds are responsive and scale with the width of the main content block with the help of &lt;a href=&#34;http://fitvidsjs.com/&#34;&gt;FitVids&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/SU3kYxJmWuQ&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post with Large Feature Image and Text</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/techie_stuff/readability-feature-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/techie_stuff/readability-feature-post/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is a sample post with a large feature image up top and tons of text. Odio ad blue bottle vinyl, 90&amp;rsquo;s narwhal commodo bitters pour-over nostrud. Ugh est hashtag in, fingerstache adipisicing laboris esse Pinterest shabby chic Portland. Shoreditch bicycle rights anim, flexitarian laboris put a bird on it vinyl cupidatat narwhal. Hashtag artisan skateboard, flannel Bushwick nesciunt salvia aute fixie do plaid post-ironic dolor McSweeney&amp;rsquo;s. Cliche pour-over chambray nulla four loko skateboard sapiente hashtag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vero laborum commodo occupy. Semiotics voluptate mumblecore pug. Cosby sweater ullamco quinoa ennui assumenda, sapiente occupy delectus lo-fi. Ea fashion axe Marfa cillum aliquip. Retro Bushwick keytar cliche. Before they sold out sustainable gastropub Marfa readymade, ethical Williamsburg skateboard brunch qui consectetur gentrify semiotics. Mustache cillum irony, fingerstache magna pour-over keffiyeh tousled selfies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cupidatat-90-s-lo-fi-authentic-try-hard&#34;&gt;Cupidatat 90&amp;rsquo;s lo-fi authentic try-hard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In pug Portland incididunt mlkshk put a bird on it vinyl quinoa. Terry Richardson shabby chic +1, scenester Tonx excepteur tempor fugiat voluptate fingerstache aliquip nisi next level. Farm-to-table hashtag Truffaut, Odd Future ex meggings gentrify single-origin coffee try-hard 90&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sartorial hoodie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Labore viral forage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tote bag selvage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DIY exercitation et id ugh tumblr church-key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incididunt umami sriracha, ethical fugiat VHS ex assumenda yr irure direct trade. Marfa Truffaut bicycle rights, kitsch placeat Etsy kogi asymmetrical. Beard locavore flexitarian, kitsch photo booth hoodie plaid ethical readymade leggings yr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesthetic odio dolore, meggings disrupt qui readymade stumptown brunch Terry Richardson pour-over gluten-free. Banksy american apparel in selfies, biodiesel flexitarian organic meh wolf quinoa gentrify banjo kogi. Readymade tofu ex, scenester dolor umami fingerstache occaecat fashion axe Carles jean shorts minim. Keffiyeh fashion axe nisi Godard mlkshk dolore. Lomo you probably haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of them eu non, Odd Future Truffaut pug keytar meggings McSweeney&amp;rsquo;s Pinterest cred. Etsy literally aute esse, eu bicycle rights qui meggings fanny pack. Gentrify leggings pug flannel duis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;forage-occaecat-cardigan-qui&#34;&gt;Forage occaecat cardigan qui&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fashion axe hella gastropub lo-fi kogi 90&amp;rsquo;s aliquip +1 veniam delectus tousled. Cred sriracha locavore gastropub kale chips, iPhone mollit sartorial. Anim dolore 8-bit, pork belly dolor photo booth aute flannel small batch. Dolor disrupt ennui, tattooed whatever salvia Banksy sartorial roof party selfies raw denim sint meh pour-over. Ennui eu cardigan sint, gentrify iPhone cornhole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever velit occaecat quis deserunt gastropub, leggings elit tousled roof party 3 wolf moon kogi pug blue bottle ea. Fashion axe shabby chic Austin quinoa pickled laborum bitters next level, disrupt deep v accusamus non fingerstache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tote bag asymmetrical elit sunt. Occaecat authentic Marfa, hella McSweeney&amp;rsquo;s next level irure veniam master cleanse. Sed hoodie letterpress artisan wolf leggings, 3 wolf moon commodo ullamco. Anim occupy ea labore Terry Richardson. Tofu ex master cleanse in whatever pitchfork banh mi, occupy fugiat fanny pack Austin authentic. Magna fugiat 3 wolf moon, labore McSweeney&amp;rsquo;s sustainable vero consectetur. Gluten-free disrupt enim, aesthetic fugiat jean shorts trust fund keffiyeh magna try-hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hoodie-duis&#34;&gt;Hoodie Duis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually salvia consectetur, hoodie duis lomo YOLO sunt sriracha. Aute pop-up brunch farm-to-table odio, salvia irure occaecat. Sriracha small batch literally skateboard. Echo Park nihil hoodie, aliquip forage artisan laboris. Trust fund reprehenderit nulla locavore. Stumptown raw denim kitsch, keffiyeh nulla twee dreamcatcher fanny pack ullamco 90&amp;rsquo;s pop-up est culpa farm-to-table. Selfies 8-bit do pug odio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thundercats-ho&#34;&gt;Thundercats Ho!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fingerstache thundercats Williamsburg, deep v scenester Banksy ennui vinyl selfies mollit biodiesel duis odio pop-up. Banksy 3 wolf moon try-hard, sapiente enim stumptown deep v ad letterpress. Squid beard brunch, exercitation raw denim yr sint direct trade. Raw denim narwhal id, flannel DIY McSweeney&amp;rsquo;s seitan. Letterpress artisan bespoke accusamus, meggings laboris consequat Truffaut qui in seitan. Sustainable cornhole Schlitz, twee Cosby sweater banh mi deep v forage letterpress flannel whatever keffiyeh. Sartorial cred irure, semiotics ethical sed blue bottle nihil letterpress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occupy et selvage squid, pug brunch blog nesciunt hashtag mumblecore skateboard yr kogi. Ugh small batch swag four loko. Fap post-ironic qui tote bag farm-to-table american apparel scenester keffiyeh vero, swag non pour-over gentrify authentic pitchfork. Schlitz scenester lo-fi voluptate, tote bag irony bicycle rights pariatur vero Vice freegan wayfarers exercitation nisi shoreditch. Chambray tofu vero sed. Street art swag literally leggings, Cosby sweater mixtape PBR lomo Banksy non in pitchfork ennui McSweeney&amp;rsquo;s selfies. Odd Future Banksy non authentic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aliquip enim artisan dolor post-ironic. Pug tote bag Marfa, deserunt pour-over Portland wolf eu odio intelligentsia american apparel ugh ea. Sunt viral et, 3 wolf moon gastropub pug id. Id fashion axe est typewriter, mlkshk Portland art party aute brunch. Sint pork belly Cosby sweater, deep v mumblecore kitsch american apparel. Try-hard direct trade tumblr sint skateboard. Adipisicing bitters excepteur biodiesel, pickled gastropub aute veniam.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Post with Images</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/techie_stuff/sample-post-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/techie_stuff/sample-post-images/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of what a post with images might look like. If you want to display two or three images next to each other responsively use &lt;code&gt;figure&lt;/code&gt; with the appropriate &lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;. Each instance of &lt;code&gt;figure&lt;/code&gt; is auto-numbered and displayed in the caption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;figures-for-images-or-video&#34;&gt;Figures (for images or video)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;one-up&#34;&gt;One Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;//farm9.staticflickr.com/8426/7758832526_cc8f681e48_b.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//farm9.staticflickr.com/8426/7758832526_cc8f681e48_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//www.flickr.com/photos/80901381@N04/7758832526/&#34; title=&#34;Morning Fog Emerging From Trees by A Guy Taking Pictures, on Flickr&#34;&gt;Morning Fog Emerging From Trees by A Guy Taking Pictures, on Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;two-up&#34;&gt;Two Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply the &lt;code&gt;half&lt;/code&gt; class like so to display two images side by side that share the same caption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;half&#34;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;https://stevehemingway.com/images/image-filename-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;https://stevehemingway.com/images/image-filename-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Caption describing these two images.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you&amp;rsquo;ll get something that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;half&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;//placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//placehold.it/600x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;//placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//placehold.it/600x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;//placehold.it/600x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;//placehold.it/600x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Two images.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;three-up&#34;&gt;Three Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply the &lt;code&gt;third&lt;/code&gt; class like so to display three images side by side that share the same caption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;third&#34;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&#34;//placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//placehold.it/600x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&#34;//placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//placehold.it/600x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&#34;//placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//placehold.it/600x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Caption describing these three images.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you&amp;rsquo;ll get something that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&#34;third&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;//placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//placehold.it/600x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;//placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//placehold.it/600x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;//placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//placehold.it/600x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;//placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//placehold.it/600x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;//placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//placehold.it/600x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;//placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//placehold.it/600x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Three images.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Readability with a Bunch of Text</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/techie_stuff/readability-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/techie_stuff/readability-post/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Portland in shoreditch Vice, labore typewriter pariatur hoodie fap sartorial Austin. Pinterest literally occupy Schlitz forage. Odio ad blue bottle vinyl, 90&amp;rsquo;s narwhal commodo bitters pour-over nostrud. Ugh est hashtag in, fingerstache adipisicing laboris esse Pinterest shabby chic Portland. Shoreditch bicycle rights anim, flexitarian laboris put a bird on it vinyl cupidatat narwhal. Hashtag artisan skateboard, flannel Bushwick nesciunt salvia aute fixie do plaid post-ironic dolor McSweeney&amp;rsquo;s. Cliche pour-over chambray nulla four loko skateboard sapiente hashtag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vero laborum commodo occupy. Semiotics voluptate mumblecore pug. Cosby sweater ullamco quinoa ennui assumenda, sapiente occupy delectus lo-fi. Ea fashion axe Marfa cillum aliquip. Retro Bushwick keytar cliche. Before they sold out sustainable gastropub Marfa readymade, ethical Williamsburg skateboard brunch qui consectetur gentrify semiotics. Mustache cillum irony, fingerstache magna pour-over keffiyeh tousled selfies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cupidatat-90-s-lo-fi-authentic-try-hard&#34;&gt;Cupidatat 90&amp;rsquo;s lo-fi authentic try-hard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In pug Portland incididunt mlkshk put a bird on it vinyl quinoa. Terry Richardson shabby chic +1, scenester Tonx excepteur tempor fugiat voluptate fingerstache aliquip nisi next level. Farm-to-table hashtag Truffaut, Odd Future ex meggings gentrify single-origin coffee try-hard 90&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sartorial hoodie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Labore viral forage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tote bag selvage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DIY exercitation et id ugh tumblr church-key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incididunt umami sriracha, ethical fugiat VHS ex assumenda yr irure direct trade. Marfa Truffaut bicycle rights, kitsch placeat Etsy kogi asymmetrical. Beard locavore flexitarian, kitsch photo booth hoodie plaid ethical readymade leggings yr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesthetic odio dolore, meggings disrupt qui readymade stumptown brunch Terry Richardson pour-over gluten-free. Banksy american apparel in selfies, biodiesel flexitarian organic meh wolf quinoa gentrify banjo kogi. Readymade tofu ex, scenester dolor umami fingerstache occaecat fashion axe Carles jean shorts minim. Keffiyeh fashion axe nisi Godard mlkshk dolore. Lomo you probably haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of them eu non, Odd Future Truffaut pug keytar meggings McSweeney&amp;rsquo;s Pinterest cred. Etsy literally aute esse, eu bicycle rights qui meggings fanny pack. Gentrify leggings pug flannel duis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;forage-occaecat-cardigan-qui&#34;&gt;Forage occaecat cardigan qui&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fashion axe hella gastropub lo-fi kogi 90&amp;rsquo;s aliquip +1 veniam delectus tousled. Cred sriracha locavore gastropub kale chips, iPhone mollit sartorial. Anim dolore 8-bit, pork belly dolor photo booth aute flannel small batch. Dolor disrupt ennui, tattooed whatever salvia Banksy sartorial roof party selfies raw denim sint meh pour-over. Ennui eu cardigan sint, gentrify iPhone cornhole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever velit occaecat quis deserunt gastropub, leggings elit tousled roof party 3 wolf moon kogi pug blue bottle ea. Fashion axe shabby chic Austin quinoa pickled laborum bitters next level, disrupt deep v accusamus non fingerstache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tote bag asymmetrical elit sunt. Occaecat authentic Marfa, hella McSweeney&amp;rsquo;s next level irure veniam master cleanse. Sed hoodie letterpress artisan wolf leggings, 3 wolf moon commodo ullamco. Anim occupy ea labore Terry Richardson. Tofu ex master cleanse in whatever pitchfork banh mi, occupy fugiat fanny pack Austin authentic. Magna fugiat 3 wolf moon, labore McSweeney&amp;rsquo;s sustainable vero consectetur. Gluten-free disrupt enim, aesthetic fugiat jean shorts trust fund keffiyeh magna try-hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hoodie-duis&#34;&gt;Hoodie Duis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually salvia consectetur, hoodie duis lomo YOLO sunt sriracha. Aute pop-up brunch farm-to-table odio, salvia irure occaecat. Sriracha small batch literally skateboard. Echo Park nihil hoodie, aliquip forage artisan laboris. Trust fund reprehenderit nulla locavore. Stumptown raw denim kitsch, keffiyeh nulla twee dreamcatcher fanny pack ullamco 90&amp;rsquo;s pop-up est culpa farm-to-table. Selfies 8-bit do pug odio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thundercats-ho&#34;&gt;Thundercats Ho!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fingerstache thundercats Williamsburg, deep v scenester Banksy ennui vinyl selfies mollit biodiesel duis odio pop-up. Banksy 3 wolf moon try-hard, sapiente enim stumptown deep v ad letterpress. Squid beard brunch, exercitation raw denim yr sint direct trade. Raw denim narwhal id, flannel DIY McSweeney&amp;rsquo;s seitan. Letterpress artisan bespoke accusamus, meggings laboris consequat Truffaut qui in seitan. Sustainable cornhole Schlitz, twee Cosby sweater banh mi deep v forage letterpress flannel whatever keffiyeh. Sartorial cred irure, semiotics ethical sed blue bottle nihil letterpress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occupy et selvage squid, pug brunch blog nesciunt hashtag mumblecore skateboard yr kogi. Ugh small batch swag four loko. Fap post-ironic qui tote bag farm-to-table american apparel scenester keffiyeh vero, swag non pour-over gentrify authentic pitchfork. Schlitz scenester lo-fi voluptate, tote bag irony bicycle rights pariatur vero Vice freegan wayfarers exercitation nisi shoreditch. Chambray tofu vero sed. Street art swag literally leggings, Cosby sweater mixtape PBR lomo Banksy non in pitchfork ennui McSweeney&amp;rsquo;s selfies. Odd Future Banksy non authentic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aliquip enim artisan dolor post-ironic. Pug tote bag Marfa, deserunt pour-over Portland wolf eu odio intelligentsia american apparel ugh ea. Sunt viral et, 3 wolf moon gastropub pug id. Id fashion axe est typewriter, mlkshk Portland art party aute brunch. Sint pork belly Cosby sweater, deep v mumblecore kitsch american apparel. Try-hard direct trade tumblr sint skateboard. Adipisicing bitters excepteur biodiesel, pickled gastropub aute veniam.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample Post</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/techie_stuff/sample-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/techie_stuff/sample-post/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Below is just about everything you&amp;rsquo;ll need to style in the theme. Check the source code to see the many embedded elements within paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;heading-1&#34;&gt;Heading 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;heading-2&#34;&gt;Heading 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;heading-3&#34;&gt;Heading 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading-4&#34;&gt;Heading 4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;heading-5&#34;&gt;Heading 5&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;heading-6&#34;&gt;Heading 6&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;body-text&#34;&gt;Body text&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, test link adipiscing elit. &lt;strong&gt;This is strong&lt;/strong&gt;. Nullam dignissim convallis est. Quisque aliquam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Smithsonian Image&#34; src=&#34;https://stevehemingway.com/images/3953273590_704e3899d5_m.jpg&#34; style=&#34;float: right;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is emphasized&lt;/em&gt;. Donec faucibus. Nunc iaculis suscipit dui. 53 = 125. Water is H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O. Nam sit amet sem. Aliquam libero nisi, imperdiet at, tincidunt nec, gravida vehicula, nisl. The New York Times &lt;cite&gt;(That’s a citation)&lt;/cite&gt;. &lt;u&gt;Underline&lt;/u&gt;. Maecenas ornare tortor. Donec sed tellus eget sapien fringilla nonummy. Mauris a ante. Suspendisse quam sem, consequat at, commodo vitae, feugiat in, nunc. Morbi imperdiet augue quis tellus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTML and &lt;abbr title=&#34;cascading stylesheets&#34;&gt;CSS&lt;abbr&gt; are our tools. Mauris a ante. Suspendisse quam sem, consequat at, commodo vitae, feugiat in, nunc. Morbi imperdiet augue quis tellus. Praesent mattis, massa quis luctus fermentum, turpis mi volutpat justo, eu volutpat enim diam eget metus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;blockquotes&#34;&gt;Blockquotes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, test link adipiscing elit. Nullam dignissim convallis est. Quisque aliquam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;list-types&#34;&gt;List Types&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ordered-lists&#34;&gt;Ordered Lists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item one

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sub item one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sub item two&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sub item three&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item two&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;unordered-lists&#34;&gt;Unordered Lists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item two&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item three&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tables&#34;&gt;Tables&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Header1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Header2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Header3&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;cell1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;cell2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;cell3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;cell4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;cell5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;cell6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;cell1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;cell2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;cell3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;cell4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;cell5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;cell6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Foot1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Foot2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Foot3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-snippets&#34;&gt;Code Snippets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Syntax highlighting via Rouge&lt;/p&gt;
#container {
  float: left;
  margin: 0 -240px 0 0;
  width: 100%;
}

&lt;p&gt;Non Pygments code example&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div id=&amp;quot;awesome&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is great isn&#39;t it?&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;buttons&#34;&gt;Buttons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make any link standout more when applying the &lt;code&gt;.btn&lt;/code&gt; class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-success&#34;&gt;Success Button&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;div markdown=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34; class=&#34;btn&#34;&gt;Primary Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div markdown=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-success&#34;&gt;Success Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div markdown=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-warning&#34;&gt;Warning Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div markdown=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-danger&#34;&gt;Danger Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div markdown=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-info&#34;&gt;Info Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>