<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2018 on Steve Hemingway&#39;s website</title>
    <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2018/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2018 on Steve Hemingway&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>(c) Steve Hemingway 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 14:46:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stevehemingway.com/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Station Pub planning application - decision time?</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2018/2018_feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 14:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2018/2018_feb/</guid>
      <description>Station Pub The long-awaited application for redevelopment of the Station Pub site (Planning Reference 17/01622/1) is likely to come before the NHDC Planning Control Committee this month, on the 15th February, probably in the Spirella Building in Letchworth. If you plan to attend, please check on the NHDC website for confirmation that the application is on the agenda. The start time of the meeting will be 7:30pm, but this application will be one of potentially many all of which will be decided at this meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January Parish News Article</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2018/jan_kpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 16:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2018/jan_kpn/</guid>
      <description>Garden Waste Bins Most of you will be aware of the new charging regime for garden waste bins being introduced this year. Removal of household waste remains a statutory obligation for the Council, and not one that it may charge for. This includes food waste which will be collected weekly from food caddies to be provided. While this will mean an additional container, the alternative would be to allow food waste to be put in the ‘residual waste’ (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>