<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2015 on Steve Hemingway&#39;s website</title>
    <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2015 on Steve Hemingway&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>(c) Steve Hemingway 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 15:26:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stevehemingway.com/2015/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>November</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/151008-knebworth-parish-news-nov/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/151008-knebworth-parish-news-nov/</guid>
      <description>NOVEMBER UPDATE NHDC Noise Application NHDC has introduced a Noise App to help deal with noise nuisance
North Hertfordshire District Council is using new technology to help deal with noise nuisance and has introduced a new Noise App. The app created by RH Environmental, allows residents with mobile devices to record incidents of nuisance noise and submit them to NHDC via the app. As unwanted noise is captured when it is actually happening, this makes it easier for residents to report problems and will allow the Council to more effectively investigate noise nuisance cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sept</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/150816-knebworth-parish-news-sep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/150816-knebworth-parish-news-sep/</guid>
      <description>SEPTEMBER UPDATE NHDC – In the Summer time NHDC full council meetings are not scheduled during school holidays to make it easier for those with school age children to stand as councillors. There are some exceptions, with the Standards Committee meeting in August (see below), and planning applications continue to be considered because of strict deadlines on the time allowed for the council to process these. Generally, the routine work of the council via the officers and staff continues ensuring that services are not interrupted, while a range of extra activities, particularly aimed at children, are run at the leisure centres and other venues through the district.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/150715-knebworth-parish-news-aug/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/150715-knebworth-parish-news-aug/</guid>
      <description>AUGUST UPDATE NHDC – Council Business Update The Council Meeting on 21 July covered a range of important issues, many of which will have an effect on North Hertfordshire residents long after the current Civic Year:
 The Council is preparing to respond to recent legislation to take into account Social Value in its tendering processes. This should make it easier for local businesses to sell goods and services to the Council</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/150613-knebworth-parish-news-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/150613-knebworth-parish-news-july/</guid>
      <description>NHDC - New Council Appointment The first meeting has been held and the appointments of Chairs, Vice-Chairs and members of the various committees made. As well as being a member of the Southern Rural Committee, I have been appointed as the Vice-Chairman of the Overview and Scrutiny Committee. The function of this committee is to &amp;lsquo;hold the executive to account&amp;rsquo;. To this end we examine many performance statistics and call each portfolio holders to present a report to us once per year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/june-2015-newsletter.docx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/june-2015-newsletter.docx/</guid>
      <description>June 2015 Newsletter The Annual Meeting of the Parish on Wednesday the 6th of May, where parking in Knebworth was one of the more burning issues under discussion. Opinion in the village is sharply divided between those who welcome the increased space available for shoppers, and those who worry about availability of parking spaces for those who work in the village, and those whose vehicles need to be near their place of work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/may-2015-newsletter.docx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/may-2015-newsletter.docx/</guid>
      <description>Review of my first year at NHDC By the time you read this column I will have served as a member of NHDC in the Knebworth Ward for (nearly) a whole year. It has been an eventful one for matters that concern the District Council: a number of planning applications for major brownfield developments, two solar farm applications, the introduction of Knebworth&amp;rsquo;s first Controlled Parking Zone and the planned move of the GP Surgery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> April</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/april-2015-newsletter.docx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/april-2015-newsletter.docx/</guid>
      <description>April 2015 Newsletter I attended a meeting on 11 March with representatives of NHDC and Stevenage Borough Council about the transfer of ownership and management of Norton Green Common to Knebworth Parish Council. The discussion was very constructive, and all parties confirmed that they could envisage no major obstacles to the transfers taking place. The legal process will take some time, and the Parish Council have yet to ratify that they wish to take on this expanded role, but I believe that this meeting was a milestone towards the goal of improving the Common as an important piece of amenity land within the Parish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/march-newsletter.docx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/march-newsletter.docx/</guid>
      <description>March Swangley&amp;rsquo;s Farm Solar PV The proposed solar farm at Swangley&amp;rsquo;s Farm has been &amp;lsquo;called in&amp;rsquo;. It will be referred to the Secretary of State for the Dept. for Communities and Local Government under the Town and Country Planning Act 1990, Section 70. This was the recommendation of the planning officer of the District Council. Documents relating to the application will now have to be examined by the Planning Inspectorate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Feb</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/february-newsletter.docx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/february-newsletter.docx/</guid>
      <description>Future of the Knebworth GP Surgery Herts County Council have now confirmed their intention of Herts County Council that its intention is to enter into an agreement with General Practice Investments, a developer, to re-develop the current library site into a new Library, a GP surgery and an associated pharmacy. This is subject to HCC and GPI finding acceptable terms for the agreement. Stephen McPartland, Richard Thake and I, together with Graham Fothergill, representing both the Patient Participation Group, and the Parish Council, had a meeting last year, with the practice manager where we learned of this general intention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/151204-knebworth-parish-news-jan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/151204-knebworth-parish-news-jan/</guid>
      <description>JANUARY UPDATE NHDC Local Plan - Preferred Options Consultation The submissions made by members of the public to the Preferred Options Consultation, undertaken as part of the development of a new Local Plan, are now available on NHDC’s website. Every written response is available to read online - go to the page you get to by searching for &amp;lsquo;&amp;ldquo;Planning Policy Online Consultations&amp;rdquo; north-herts&amp;rsquo;.
NHDC’s Grants Policy A report on Grants Policy is due to be discussed at the meeting of Cabinet on the 15th December.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>