<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Steve Hemingway&#39;s website</title>
    <link>https://stevehemingway.com/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Steve Hemingway&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>(c) Steve Hemingway 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stevehemingway.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-build and Custom Build Register</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/self-build-register/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/self-build-register/</guid>
      <description>You can use The North Herts Self Build and Custom Build Register to register yourself as wanting a plot in the District for a self-build home.
New rules came into effect on 31 October 2016 which amended the Self-build and Custom Housebuilding Act 2015 and implemented Chapter 2 of the Housing and Planning Act 2016 which sets out provisions to support self-build and custom housebuilding.
This means that the second and final part of the Right to Build, placing a duty on relevant authorities to make land available to meet the demand on their self-build and custom housebuilding registers, has now come into force and the Right to Build is now fully implemented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregates Yard Planning Application</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/chas_lowe_sandyard_application/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/chas_lowe_sandyard_application/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I spoke at a Planning Control Committee meeting. I was supporting the Parish Council, in the form of Cllr Roger Willcocks, in objecting to application, &amp;lsquo;17/02652/1 - 135A LONDON ROAD, KNEBWORTH, SG3 6EX&amp;rsquo;. This is the conversion of the old aggregates yard, part of Chas Lowe &amp;amp; Sons, into two 2-bed flats and two commercial (retail) units. The grounds on which we objected were principally to do with parking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NORTH HERTFORDSHIRE DISTRICT COUNCIL – MARCH UPDATE</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/march_update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/march_update/</guid>
      <description>Station Pub Planning Application (Ref 17/01622/1) It was good to see the support at the Pop Up Pub in the village hall last month, held as part of the SOSPUB Campaign (see photo). The planning application for the Station Pub, which retains a pub but includes development of part of the site into flats, is still to come before the NHDC Planning Control Committee, this month’s meeting is on Thursday 15th March, 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steve Hemingway&#39;s Corner of the World Wide Web</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/notes/</guid>
      <description>I decided to load up my regular columns for Knebworth Parish News onto this website. I occasionally post things here, but for anything I have to say that can be fitted into 280 characters, I tend to use Twitter.
This website does not use cookies, but even if it did you should not be worried about them.
I don&amp;rsquo;t keep any information about you, although I am registered with the ICO, just in case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Do I Call When I Want to Call The Council?</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/who_do_i_call/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 17:03:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/who_do_i_call/</guid>
      <description>North Herts District Council Tel: 01462-474000 Email: service@north-herts.gov.uk Twitter: @NorthHertsDC
Web: www.north-herts.gov.uk
Contact NHDC about all the following:
 Vandalism Noise Bonfires and Construction Dust Licensed Premises Stray Dogs Public Toilets (not in villages) Abandoned or burned-out vehicles Dog Fouling issues Council Tax/Housing Benefit NHDC Housing (for the following:)  Actual or threatened homelessness Housing debt advice Advice on any housing issue Common Housing Register queries   NHDC are responsible for parks and gardens in the towns in the District, but for these, call the contractor directly:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Churchgate</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/churchgate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 17:42:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/churchgate/</guid>
      <description>Councillors to consider potential scheme to regenerate Hitchin’s Churchgate Centre A new potential joint venture opportunity for the regeneration of the Churchgate Centre in Hitchin will be discussed at a meeting of North Hertfordshire District Council’s (NHDC) Full Council on 8 February. The potential joint venture between the Council and Shearer Property Group would see a ‘face-lift’ of the existing shopping centre, improving the quality of the units available and in turn making them more attractive to retailers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Station Pub planning application - decision time?</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2018/2018_feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 14:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2018/2018_feb/</guid>
      <description>Station Pub The long-awaited application for redevelopment of the Station Pub site (Planning Reference 17/01622/1) is likely to come before the NHDC Planning Control Committee this month, on the 15th February, probably in the Spirella Building in Letchworth. If you plan to attend, please check on the NHDC website for confirmation that the application is on the agenda. The start time of the meeting will be 7:30pm, but this application will be one of potentially many all of which will be decided at this meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January Parish News Article</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2018/jan_kpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 16:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2018/jan_kpn/</guid>
      <description>Garden Waste Bins Most of you will be aware of the new charging regime for garden waste bins being introduced this year. Removal of household waste remains a statutory obligation for the Council, and not one that it may charge for. This includes food waste which will be collected weekly from food caddies to be provided. While this will mean an additional container, the alternative would be to allow food waste to be put in the ‘residual waste’ (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Plan, Brown Bins, Dec Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/dec_newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/dec_newsletter/</guid>
      <description>New Contract for Waste Collection NHDC is progressing with the new contract for the household waste collection service, jointly with East Herts. The winning bidder was a company called Urbaser who, while new to North Herts are the third largest environmental services provider across Europe. The contract for basic waste collection has been agreed with a more minor part of the contract to be signed. The contract represents a significant saving for Council Tax payers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herfordshire Year of Physical Activity</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/hyopa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/hyopa/</guid>
      <description>Funding Fact Sheet 2018 will be the Year of Physical Activity in Hertfordshire &amp;ndash; an initiative being led by Hertfordshire&amp;rsquo;s 10 District and Borough Councils, Public Health Hertfordshire and the Herts Sports and Physical Activity Partnership. The year will be kicking off on January 1st.**
The aim of the project is to make Hertfordshire, England&amp;rsquo;s most active county and in doing so, help to shift some of the stubborn inactivity levels to be found across the county.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travellers site at Pottersheath, Codicote</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/nov_kpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 11:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/nov_kpn/</guid>
      <description>Complexities of the Planning Process An On-Going Case An undecided planning application for a Gypsy and Traveller site at Pottersheath illustrates some of the complexity around the interpretation of national planning policy, as well as the diverse roles of the Local Planning Authority (NHDC), the local Ward councillors, the Planning Control Committee, as supported by the planning officers and the Planning Inspectorate. The law provides for some local autonomy in deciding planning applications, but this often falls short of what those who are most affected would want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October Parish News Article</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/oct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 16:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/oct/</guid>
      <description>NHDC Corporate Plan Approved The NHDC Corporate Plan was approved at the Council Meeting this month. It has, in addition to specifying how the Council plans to deliver its objectives, a useful set of statistics about the District. In common with most of the UK, the population of the District is getting older, but by a huge relative amount in the case of some age groups. The number of residents who are 90 years or older is expected to increase by around two and a half times by 2037, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 2017 Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/oct_kpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 11:42:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/oct_kpn/</guid>
      <description>NHDC Corporate Plan Approved The NHDC Corporate Plan was approved at the Council Meeting this month. It has, in addition to specifying how the Council plans to deliver its objectives, a useful set of statistics about the District. In common with most of the UK, the population of the District is getting older, but by a huge relative amount in the case of some age groups. The number of residents who are 90 years or older is expected to increase by around two and a half times by 2037, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Byelaws, Planning Portal Software, Chas Lowe site</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/sept_kpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 10:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/sept_kpn/</guid>
      <description>Public Consultation on Revoking of NHDC Byelaws NHDC has reviewed its byelaws, some of which date back to the 19th Century, and have no relevance today. The recommendation is to revoke all existing byelaws with the exception of the 2007 Acupuncture, Tattooing, Semi-Permanent Skin-Colouring, Cosmetic Piercing and Electrolysis byelaw.
In most cases the byelaws, many of which related to enforcement of sanitary practices in commercial premises and to the prohibition of antisocial behaviour in public places have been superseded by more modern national statutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August Newsletter - Knebworth Parish News</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/august_kpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 12:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/august_kpn/</guid>
      <description>Station Pub Planning Application A planning application, Ref. 17/01622/1, which has been submitted to NHDC to re-develop the site of the Station Hotel (aka the Station Pub) to provide nine two bed and five one bed dwellings, in addition to the existing bar area. The &amp;lsquo;Save Our Station Pub&amp;rsquo; campaign team is looking at valid planning grounds on which this application might be challenged. Please see the article elsewhere in this edition for more information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July Newsletter, published first in Knebworth Parish News</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/jul-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 20:49:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/jul-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>We have had a long period of elections, with the General Election following closely on the heels of the County elections. Stephen McPartland was re-elected as the Member of Parliament for Stevenage, which includes Knebworth, Codicote, Datchworth and Aston. Let us hope that Westminster MPs from all constituencies from across the country focus on the job in hand: which is to make the laws that will shape society in the country for years to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Plan Submission</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/local-plan-submission/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 14:34:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/local-plan-submission/</guid>
      <description>Following the meeting and resolutions of Full Council on 11 April 2017, the new Local Plan for North Hertfordshire has now been submitted to the Secretary of State for examination.
The Planning Inspectorate have advised the Council that Inspector Simon Berkeley BA MA MRTPI has been appointed to conduct the examination. The precise date for the opening of any formal hearing part of the examination into the Local Plan will be decided by the Inspector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CAA consultation</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/caa-consultation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 16:07:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/caa-consultation/</guid>
      <description>I received the following email letter today, and I thought it would be useful to share it with local residents. Luton airport is an important local employer, as well as a very important public transport hub for us all, but it does create some problems. The CAA are keen to hear your views.
Steve.
Letter from CAA Dear Cllr Hemingway
The Civil Aviation Authority (CAA) is currently consulting on a new decision making process for all future airspace changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June Update</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/june_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 12:17:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/june_17/</guid>
      <description>On 4th May, elections were held for the County Council. Richard Thake was re-elected to represent Knebworth, as well as Codicote, St Pauls Walden, Kimpton, Wymondley and St Ippolyts. Residents are often unclear about the difference between the County and District councils. The County Council runs social care, children&amp;rsquo;s services (including schools) and the highways (other than motorways and trunk roads), and for Hertfordshire has a budget of around £1.85 billion, spending £1,625 per head of population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>County Election Results 4 May 2017</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 09:51:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/elections/</guid>
      <description>Elections in North Herts Congratulations to Michael Muir, Judi Billing, David Barnard, Derek Ashley, Richard Thake, Simon Bloxham, Terry Hone, Fiona Hill and Steve Jarvis for winning County Council seats.
Also congratulations to Ray Shakespeare-Smith and Sarah Dingley in District bye-elections.
For full results in North Herts visit the NHDC website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My May 2017 Newsletter for the Knebworth Parish News</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/may_kpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 11:25:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/may_kpn/</guid>
      <description>Local Plan Update In March officers at NHDC finished cataloguing the 5,675 responses to the Local Plan consultation from last year. The role of NHDC in that consultation was only to collect and organize the responses, and to make sure the correct procedure was followed, as part of the overall, multi-stage process as set out by legislation that must be followed to arrive at a Local Plan.
The next step is the submission to the Secretary of State for Communities and Local Government, for the plan to be reviewed by the government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toeing the Party Line</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/letter_about_whipping/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 09:42:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/letter_about_whipping/</guid>
      <description>The following letter appeared in the various North Herts editions of today&amp;rsquo;s Comet newspaper. You can access the &amp;lsquo;e-edition&amp;rsquo; (with some difficulty) via this link.
 Dear Sir,
In response to the &amp;lsquo;anonymous&amp;rsquo; (why?) correspondent who stated that the Conservative Group has adopted rules regarding voting. I am sure they are aware that all Parties, including the Liberal Democrats, have rules in place that require members to support agreed Party positions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/april_newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 12:31:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/april_newsletter/</guid>
      <description>This article appeared in the April edition of the Knebworth Parish News.
Chas Lowe Redevelopment You will be aware by now of proposals by McCarthy and Stone to re-develop the former Chas Lowe builders&amp;rsquo; merchants site in London Road. I am not aware of any planning application yet, and so it is difficult to comment on proposals. A leaflet, which lacks details, has been delivered to residents.
What is clear is that distortions in the housing market have given rise to a situation where land for accommodation of the elderly has a higher value than almost any other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2016/january-newsletter.docx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2016/january-newsletter.docx/</guid>
      <description>Application to redevelop the GP Surgery at 1 Stevenage Road Negotiations are continuing to find a better building for the Knebworth and Marymead Medical Practice. I have had meetings with Stephen McPartland and Richard Thake to establish how to move forward on this problem. The owner of the existing surgery had submitted a planning application to redevelop the site, although this has now been withdrawn. The site currently occupied by Knebworth Library in St Martins Road is currently the preferred location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/151008-knebworth-parish-news-nov/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/151008-knebworth-parish-news-nov/</guid>
      <description>NOVEMBER UPDATE NHDC Noise Application NHDC has introduced a Noise App to help deal with noise nuisance
North Hertfordshire District Council is using new technology to help deal with noise nuisance and has introduced a new Noise App. The app created by RH Environmental, allows residents with mobile devices to record incidents of nuisance noise and submit them to NHDC via the app. As unwanted noise is captured when it is actually happening, this makes it easier for residents to report problems and will allow the Council to more effectively investigate noise nuisance cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sept</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/150816-knebworth-parish-news-sep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/150816-knebworth-parish-news-sep/</guid>
      <description>SEPTEMBER UPDATE NHDC – In the Summer time NHDC full council meetings are not scheduled during school holidays to make it easier for those with school age children to stand as councillors. There are some exceptions, with the Standards Committee meeting in August (see below), and planning applications continue to be considered because of strict deadlines on the time allowed for the council to process these. Generally, the routine work of the council via the officers and staff continues ensuring that services are not interrupted, while a range of extra activities, particularly aimed at children, are run at the leisure centres and other venues through the district.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/150715-knebworth-parish-news-aug/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/150715-knebworth-parish-news-aug/</guid>
      <description>AUGUST UPDATE NHDC – Council Business Update The Council Meeting on 21 July covered a range of important issues, many of which will have an effect on North Hertfordshire residents long after the current Civic Year:
 The Council is preparing to respond to recent legislation to take into account Social Value in its tendering processes. This should make it easier for local businesses to sell goods and services to the Council</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/150613-knebworth-parish-news-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/150613-knebworth-parish-news-july/</guid>
      <description>NHDC - New Council Appointment The first meeting has been held and the appointments of Chairs, Vice-Chairs and members of the various committees made. As well as being a member of the Southern Rural Committee, I have been appointed as the Vice-Chairman of the Overview and Scrutiny Committee. The function of this committee is to &amp;lsquo;hold the executive to account&amp;rsquo;. To this end we examine many performance statistics and call each portfolio holders to present a report to us once per year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/june-2015-newsletter.docx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/june-2015-newsletter.docx/</guid>
      <description>June 2015 Newsletter The Annual Meeting of the Parish on Wednesday the 6th of May, where parking in Knebworth was one of the more burning issues under discussion. Opinion in the village is sharply divided between those who welcome the increased space available for shoppers, and those who worry about availability of parking spaces for those who work in the village, and those whose vehicles need to be near their place of work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/may-2015-newsletter.docx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/may-2015-newsletter.docx/</guid>
      <description>Review of my first year at NHDC By the time you read this column I will have served as a member of NHDC in the Knebworth Ward for (nearly) a whole year. It has been an eventful one for matters that concern the District Council: a number of planning applications for major brownfield developments, two solar farm applications, the introduction of Knebworth&amp;rsquo;s first Controlled Parking Zone and the planned move of the GP Surgery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> April</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/april-2015-newsletter.docx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/april-2015-newsletter.docx/</guid>
      <description>April 2015 Newsletter I attended a meeting on 11 March with representatives of NHDC and Stevenage Borough Council about the transfer of ownership and management of Norton Green Common to Knebworth Parish Council. The discussion was very constructive, and all parties confirmed that they could envisage no major obstacles to the transfers taking place. The legal process will take some time, and the Parish Council have yet to ratify that they wish to take on this expanded role, but I believe that this meeting was a milestone towards the goal of improving the Common as an important piece of amenity land within the Parish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/march-newsletter.docx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/march-newsletter.docx/</guid>
      <description>March Swangley&amp;rsquo;s Farm Solar PV The proposed solar farm at Swangley&amp;rsquo;s Farm has been &amp;lsquo;called in&amp;rsquo;. It will be referred to the Secretary of State for the Dept. for Communities and Local Government under the Town and Country Planning Act 1990, Section 70. This was the recommendation of the planning officer of the District Council. Documents relating to the application will now have to be examined by the Planning Inspectorate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Feb</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/february-newsletter.docx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/february-newsletter.docx/</guid>
      <description>Future of the Knebworth GP Surgery Herts County Council have now confirmed their intention of Herts County Council that its intention is to enter into an agreement with General Practice Investments, a developer, to re-develop the current library site into a new Library, a GP surgery and an associated pharmacy. This is subject to HCC and GPI finding acceptable terms for the agreement. Stephen McPartland, Richard Thake and I, together with Graham Fothergill, representing both the Patient Participation Group, and the Parish Council, had a meeting last year, with the practice manager where we learned of this general intention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/151204-knebworth-parish-news-jan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2015/151204-knebworth-parish-news-jan/</guid>
      <description>JANUARY UPDATE NHDC Local Plan - Preferred Options Consultation The submissions made by members of the public to the Preferred Options Consultation, undertaken as part of the development of a new Local Plan, are now available on NHDC’s website. Every written response is available to read online - go to the page you get to by searching for &amp;lsquo;&amp;ldquo;Planning Policy Online Consultations&amp;rdquo; north-herts&amp;rsquo;.
NHDC’s Grants Policy A report on Grants Policy is due to be discussed at the meeting of Cabinet on the 15th December.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knebworth Parish News, Sept 2014</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2014/september/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2014/september/</guid>
      <description>Swangley&amp;rsquo;s Farm Solar PV As you may already be aware, there is a proposal to build a &amp;lsquo;solar farm&amp;rsquo; on one of the fields comprising Swangley&amp;rsquo;s Farm. This will involve covering much of the field with solar panels, fixed on metal frames, installing a container-sized inverter building, and connecting the latter to the grid. The field is at the junction of Swangley&amp;rsquo;s Lane and Baines Lane, at the eastern boundary of the parish, where it borders Datchworth Parish.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>