<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hcc on Steve Hemingway&#39;s website</title>
    <link>https://stevehemingway.com/categories/hcc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hcc on Steve Hemingway&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>(c) Steve Hemingway 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stevehemingway.com/categories/hcc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is responsible for controlling verge parking</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/verge-parking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/verge-parking/</guid>
      <description>Over our long, wet winter in our congested village with its inadequate parking facilities, one issue comes up time and time again. This is the anti-social habit of drivers parking with one (or more) pairs of wheels on the grass verge, turning it into a muddy wreck.
The solution is to contact:
 HCC – Herts Highways are responsible for putting bollards on grass verges as these areas are part of the highway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Plan, Brown Bins, Dec Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/dec_newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/dec_newsletter/</guid>
      <description>New Contract for Waste Collection NHDC is progressing with the new contract for the household waste collection service, jointly with East Herts. The winning bidder was a company called Urbaser who, while new to North Herts are the third largest environmental services provider across Europe. The contract for basic waste collection has been agreed with a more minor part of the contract to be signed. The contract represents a significant saving for Council Tax payers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herfordshire Year of Physical Activity</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/hyopa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/2017/hyopa/</guid>
      <description>Funding Fact Sheet 2018 will be the Year of Physical Activity in Hertfordshire &amp;ndash; an initiative being led by Hertfordshire&amp;rsquo;s 10 District and Borough Councils, Public Health Hertfordshire and the Herts Sports and Physical Activity Partnership. The year will be kicking off on January 1st.**
The aim of the project is to make Hertfordshire, England&amp;rsquo;s most active county and in doing so, help to shift some of the stubborn inactivity levels to be found across the county.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>