<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Steve Hemingway's Blog - 2014</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/feeds/2014.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://stevehemingway.github.io/</id><updated>2014-12-01T15:36:40+00:00</updated><entry><title>December Article</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/december-article.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-12-01T15:36:40+00:00</published><updated>2014-12-01T15:36:40+00:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2014-12-01:/december-article.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Description = &amp;#8220;Waste Collection, Local Plan&amp;#8221;
lang: &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EN&lt;/span&gt;-gb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Waste&amp;nbsp;Collection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Percival in last month&amp;#8217;s Parish News commented: &amp;#8220;contracted refuse collectors routinely dump emptied wheelie bins at random on pavements all around our village&amp;#8221;. I contacted the officer at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; responsible for the waste and recycling contract with …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Description = &amp;#8220;Waste Collection, Local Plan&amp;#8221;
lang: &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EN&lt;/span&gt;-gb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Waste&amp;nbsp;Collection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Percival in last month&amp;#8217;s Parish News commented: &amp;#8220;contracted refuse collectors routinely dump emptied wheelie bins at random on pavements all around our village&amp;#8221;. I contacted the officer at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; responsible for the waste and recycling contract with Veolia and this is what she wrote about the&amp;nbsp;contract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;The operatives should be placing any bins or boxes back where they
came from. They, in particular, should not be leaving them obstructing
driveways or footpaths unnecessarily. Windy days can be a problem
generally however if they are returned to the boundary of a property
they are often next to a wall or hedge which helps prevent this&amp;nbsp;problem.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do have Waste Services Officers out monitoring the contract, so I
have copied [the relevant officer] in who will be about to check some
of the streets in Knebworth over the next few&amp;nbsp;collections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is clear that the Veolia operatives are not perfect, but hopefully
this reminder will provoke an improvement in the service. If residents
notice any problems they can contact the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; helpdesk on 0800 328 6023
who will monitor the level of complaints from Knebworth. Alternatively
feel free to contact me about this&amp;nbsp;directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;North Hertfordshire Local&amp;nbsp;Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; is due to vote on moving to the next stage in the production of the
Local Plan at its meeting on 27th November. This will approve the Local
Development Scheme which sets out the timetable for consultation, but
will include the publication of the &amp;#8220;Preferred Options&amp;#8221;, i.e. sites
which the council have put forward as suitable for development.
Consultation on this document, as well as on the numerous planning
policies that together with the sites form the Plan, will take place
from early December through to the first week of February (these are
provisional dates and are still to be confirmed). Full information about
the proposals will be available in the Library and on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Planning Matters -&amp;nbsp;Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Solar Farm &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PV&lt;/span&gt; Applications&lt;/em&gt;: The Swangley’s Lane application was due to
be discussed by &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Planning Control at its committee meeting on
13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; November but the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; officer wrote to advise me that it
had been withdrawn from the agenda as the applicant had written to the
planning officers &amp;#8220;setting out additional proposals to mitigate the
impact of the scheme on the surrounding landscape and to address the
concerns regarding the impact of the development on the Green Belt.&amp;#8221;.
There will now be further public consultation and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; expect it to be
discussed at the planning meeting on 18&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; December.
Consideration of the Three Houses Lane solar farm has been delayed
because of errors in the application and no date is yet scheduled for it
to come before the planning&amp;nbsp;committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knebworth Park Cricket Club&lt;/em&gt;: Consideration of this application was
deferred by &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; planning because of late submission of a revised design
of the pavilion and of a Flood Risk Assessment and drainage plans. It is
expected that the application will be reconsidered at the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Planning
Control committee meeting on 18&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;111 London Road&lt;/em&gt;: Following our objections, the developer provided a
revised application with extra parking spaces and a contribution to
affordable housing in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; area and the committee has now accepted&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2014"></category></entry><entry><title>November Article</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/november-article-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-01T15:36:40+00:00</published><updated>2014-11-01T15:36:40+00:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2014-11-01:/november-article-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;Surgery, Solar Farm, Cricket Club, Bulwer&amp;nbsp;Lytton&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Application to redevelop the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GP&lt;/span&gt; Surgery at 1 Stevenage&amp;nbsp;Road&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future of Knebworth and Marymead &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GP&lt;/span&gt; Practice at 1 London Road has
been uncertain for a considerable time. Various proposals for it moving
have been discussed without any coming close to fruition. A number of
residents were surprised to read about an application to redevelop the
surgery into eight one-bedroom flats, submitted by the owner of the&amp;nbsp;site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I understand it, this application was submitted to protect the
position of the owner in the event the surgery gives notice to quit. The
practice may do so at short notice under the current tenure, which, so
it is understandable that the landlord should enact some contingency
plans. The current surgery is outdated and unsatisfactory in a number of
ways: it would clearly be better if more modern premises were available,
whether on the current site, or another one. To find out more about the
options available I will be meeting with the surgery and a number of
interested parties in the second half of&amp;nbsp;October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Knebworth Park Cricket&amp;nbsp;Club&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the order of sixty people turned up to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt; Planning Control
Committee on Monday 13th October to hear it consider the application for
a new clubhouse and two pitches on Jubilee Fields, to the east of Park
Lane opposite the Alms Houses and Mulberry Cottages in Old Knebworth.
Feelings ran high, with strong arguments on both sides. The committee
decided to oppose the application. A date for it to be considered by
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; has not yet been set. I am sure that when a date has been set there
will be a big turnout at the Council Chamber in Letchworth. You can be
sure that I&amp;#8217;ll be present and will be writing about the&amp;nbsp;decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Bulwer Lytton&amp;nbsp;application&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The developer has submitted an application to develop thirteen detached
houses on the site of the former care home, Bulwer Lytton House. Some of
these houses are close to neighbouring properties, they occupy a large
part of the plan of the site, and the plan allows for the retention of
fewer trees than the previous application, for outline planning
permission, submitted on behalf of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HCC&lt;/span&gt; which owned the site. I will be
trying to persuade the Planning Control Committee at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; to reject this
application at its meeting on the 16th&amp;nbsp;October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;111 London Road&amp;nbsp;Application&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The long awaited amended application for twenty-six one-bedroom flats on
the site of the former boy&amp;#8217;s home at 111 London Road was submitted and
reviewed by the Parish Council last month. The Planning Committee were
not persuaded that the changes addressed any of the grounds on which
they objected to the application the last time it was&amp;nbsp;considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Pondcroft Road, Milestone Road, Gun Lane Draft Traffic Regulation&amp;nbsp;Order&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The consultation about introducing a Controlled Parking Zone in some
roads near Knebworth railway station finished in early October.
Unfortunately too early for me to draw attention to it in the previous
edition of this newsletter. I have not received any indication of the
results of this consultation from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;, as of today, but to the extent
that I received any feedback the balance of opinion was opposed to the
proposals, albeit with a number of residents being&amp;nbsp;enthusiastic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, although not part of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TRO&lt;/span&gt;, a preliminary
consultation to reduce the amount of parking in Watton Road took place.
I received one or two calls, but not enough to be confident of gauging
the general mood of residents in the road, which does suffer a great
deal as a &amp;#8216;rat run&amp;#8217; to parts of Stevenage, as well as being the main
route to the A602&amp;nbsp;south.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Solar&amp;nbsp;Farms&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The planning application for the proposed Solar Farm at Swangley’s Farm
has not yet been scheduled to come before a Planning Control Committee,
but the protestors continue to challenge the application. As I
understand it, an attempt is being made to challenge the decision to
dispense with an Environmental Impact Assessment as part of the
application. I expect that the application will go before &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; this&amp;nbsp;month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a second application to build a solar farm, this time on land
south of Three Houses Lane, north of Codicote. There was a lively
discussion about this application at the Parish Council Planning
Committee which was held on Monday 13th October. Although this is a
sparsely populated part of Knebworth Parish, a number of residents took
part in the Public Participation. The Parish Council decided to object
to the application on the grounds that it felt it was inappropriate for
the Green&amp;nbsp;Belt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fly&amp;nbsp;Tipping&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have had a number of reports of fly tipping around Knebworth, made
directly to me. North Hertfordshire District Council treats fly-tipping
very seriously and will prosecute anyone caught fly-tipping waste. Fly
tipping is irresponsible, dangerous and expensive to clear up. There is
a form on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; website (just search for ‘fly tipping’) or feel free
to contact&amp;nbsp;me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fly tipping on private land is not the responsibility of the local
authority, but on the public highway it is. For larger scale fly tipping
the Environment Agency has a statutory duty to investigate fly tipping
when the waste may pose a serious threat to the&amp;nbsp;environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;North Hertfordshire Local&amp;nbsp;Plan&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Local Development Scheme has now been published. It can be viewed on
the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; website (under Planning, Planning Policy and Projects). This
sets out a timetable for the development of the Local Plan. This process
includes several rounds of consultation, including one on the ‘Preferred
Options’ and on the submission itself, before it is formally submitted
to the Secretary of State for Communities and Local Government in April&amp;nbsp;2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as anyone can tell, writing in mid-October, we are still on
course for submission of the preferred options paper, including the
potential housing sites, to Full Council on 27th November 2014.
Consultation on this paper is scheduled for the fifth of December to the
end of January 2015. Formal submission of the final version likely to
take place in Summer&amp;nbsp;2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in finding out which parts of the District are
likely to see residential growth in the ‘plan period’ to 2031 please
check the Council’s website for the Full Council agenda which should be
available online from around&amp;nbsp;mid-November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been reports recently of extra clarification from the current
Secretary of State which appears to give priority to preservation of the
Green Belt over the directive to meet objectively assessed housing
needs, both ours and those of adjacent authorities. These conflicting
messages from Central Government need in my view to be resolved very
rapidly. I am joining with a number of my fellow district councillors in
urging the planning officers and members at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; to press for such&amp;nbsp;resolution.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2014"></category></entry><entry><title>October ArticleDescription = “Surgery, Solar Farm, Cricket Club, Grants, Norton Green”</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/october-articledescription-surgery-solar-farm-cricket-club-grants-norton-green-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-01T15:36:40+00:00</published><updated>2014-10-01T15:36:40+00:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2014-10-01:/october-articledescription-surgery-solar-farm-cricket-club-grants-norton-green-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Planning&amp;nbsp;Matters&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several significant applications are due to be considered by the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KPC&lt;/span&gt;
Planning Committee on 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; October. Please submit your
comments to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; before the deadline if you have views, and/or raise
them with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KPC&lt;/span&gt; Planning Committee. As in all Parish and District
Council meetings, members …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Planning&amp;nbsp;Matters&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several significant applications are due to be considered by the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KPC&lt;/span&gt;
Planning Committee on 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; October. Please submit your
comments to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; before the deadline if you have views, and/or raise
them with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KPC&lt;/span&gt; Planning Committee. As in all Parish and District
Council meetings, members of the public are welcome to attend committee&amp;nbsp;meetings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knebworth &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GP&lt;/span&gt; Surgery&lt;/strong&gt;: An application has been made for 1 Stevenage
Road a proposal for eight one-bedroom flats on the site of the Knebworth
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GP&lt;/span&gt; Surgery – the deadline for comments to be made to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; is
9&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; October, and as &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HCC&lt;/span&gt; is responsible for the provision of
the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GP&lt;/span&gt; surgeries, Knebworth’s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HCC&lt;/span&gt; representative, Cllr Richard Thake, is
fully&amp;nbsp;involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solar Farms&lt;/strong&gt;: At its last planning meeting &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KPC&lt;/span&gt; objected to the
proposed Swangley’s Lane Solar Farm, having had extensive discussion and
views expressed by residents, other members of the public and the
developer, and will be considering a second solar farm at Crouch Green,
on Three Houses Lane (deadline 16&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; October).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knebworth Park Cricket Club&lt;/strong&gt;: An amended application is due to be
considered (deadline 30&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; October).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other residential&lt;/strong&gt;: A new application for the Bulwer Lytton House
site in Lytton Fields (deadline 16&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; October) and an
application for proposed development at 111 London Road will also be&amp;nbsp;considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; – Capital and Grant Funding&amp;nbsp;Awards&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two awards of additional funding have been made by &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;committees:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A grant of &amp;pound;7,000 has been awarded to Knebworth Parish Council by
    the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Rural Community Halls Capital Fund. This will allow a major
    upgrade to the heating system in the Village Hall, just in time for
    the cold winter&amp;nbsp;months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Knebworth Day Centre for the vulnerable and elderly received a
    boost when it received a grant of &amp;pound;1,000 from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;’s Southern Rural
    Area Committee to help with operational costs. Knebworth Day Centre,
    a not-for-profit organisation staffed by ten volunteers, has
    provided social activities for elderly and frail people for 25
    years, and currently around 15 members meet every Monday from 10am
    to&amp;nbsp;3pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Parking – Proposals for Further&amp;nbsp;Restrictions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that some of you were able to attend the meeting in the Village
Hall on 23&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; September when proposals to introduce further
parking restrictions in Pondcroft Road, Milestone Road, Deanscroft, Gun
Lane, Gun Road and (to a minor extent) Station Road. There is also a
proposal, although at an earlier stage, to introduce parking
restrictions in Watton Road. Full details are available in the Library
or on the Parish Council and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; websites. Please be quick as the
deadline for comments is 3rd October – you can email comments to
&lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;&amp;#116;&amp;#114;&amp;#97;&amp;#110;&amp;#115;&amp;#112;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#116;&amp;#64;&amp;#110;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#116;&amp;#104;&amp;#45;&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#116;&amp;#115;&amp;#46;&amp;#103;&amp;#111;&amp;#118;&amp;#46;&amp;#117;&amp;#107;"&gt;&amp;#116;&amp;#114;&amp;#97;&amp;#110;&amp;#115;&amp;#112;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#116;&amp;#64;&amp;#110;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#116;&amp;#104;&amp;#45;&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#116;&amp;#115;&amp;#46;&amp;#103;&amp;#111;&amp;#118;&amp;#46;&amp;#117;&amp;#107;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Norton Green&amp;nbsp;Common&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fly Tipping and illegal access to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSSI&lt;/span&gt; on the Common continues to be
a problem. Representatives of Natural England and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HCC&lt;/span&gt; have just been out
to look at the tipping and have proposed a solution to restrict access
on the Common by introducing bollards right along up to the beginning of
the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSSI&lt;/span&gt;. Knebworth Estates have agreed pay for the bollards as they
will also stop access to their woodland, which has suffered from fly
tipping in the&amp;nbsp;past.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2014"></category></entry><entry><title>Knebworth Parish News, Sept 2014</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/knebworth-parish-news-sept-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-09-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-09-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2014-09-01:/knebworth-parish-news-sept-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;modified: 2020-05-09
lang: &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EN&lt;/span&gt;-gb
Summary: &amp;#8220;Proposal to build a solar&amp;nbsp;farm&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Swangley&amp;#8217;s Farm Solar &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may already be aware, there is a proposal to build a &amp;#8216;solar farm&amp;#8217;
on one of the fields comprising Swangley&amp;#8217;s Farm. This will involve
covering much of the field with …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;modified: 2020-05-09
lang: &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EN&lt;/span&gt;-gb
Summary: &amp;#8220;Proposal to build a solar&amp;nbsp;farm&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Swangley&amp;#8217;s Farm Solar &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may already be aware, there is a proposal to build a &amp;#8216;solar farm&amp;#8217;
on one of the fields comprising Swangley&amp;#8217;s Farm. This will involve
covering much of the field with solar panels, fixed on metal frames,
installing a container-sized inverter building, and connecting the
latter to the grid. The field is at the junction of Swangley&amp;#8217;s Lane and
Baines Lane, at the eastern boundary of the parish, where it borders
Datchworth Parish. The field is approximately fifty acres. Full details
are available on the website of Solstice Renewables, the developer, as
well as on the Parish Council&amp;nbsp;website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another proposal has been made for a similar-sized solar farm at Three
Houses Farm, between Three Houses Lane and Node Wood. This is in the
western &amp;#8216;finger&amp;#8217; of the Parish, which encompasses Rusling End and Three
Houses Lane. No planning application has been made for this development
as yet, so it is too early to say any more about it. It is notable that
a number of these developments have been proposed in nearby parishes,
including in Graveley and Langley. This may be linked to the current
subsidy levels, which are due to change in April&amp;nbsp;2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is expected that the fully validated applications for these two solar
farms will have been accepted by &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; by September. In the case of the
Swangley&amp;#8217;s Farm site, a &amp;#8216;screening opinion&amp;#8217; has already been received
and approved. This is a preliminary enquiry to determine what documents
must be accompany in the application itself. The approval of this
screening opinion application does not have any bearing on whether the
development application itself will be&amp;nbsp;approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process for deciding on these applications is as follows. Once the
application has been validated, it will be uploaded to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; planning
portal. The application will be examined by the Parish Council (or which
I am a member) at a meeting of the Planning Committee, typically the
first meeting after the application has been validated. Members of the
public are welcome to attend this meeting. A period, typically fifteen
minutes before the meeting formally starts, is allocated for members of
the public to give their views. The discussion about the application is
held in public, and, usually, the committee decides whether it has any
objection to the application, and, if it has, on what ground(s) it
objects. It may also decide to support an application in some cases, or
merely to not object to&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to the process is deciding on which ground or grounds the
committee objects to the application. Planning applications must be
decided in relation to the relevant planning legislation. If an
application is not consistent with the Local Plan, or is outside the
guidelines defined in the national and local guidelines, then the Parish
Council may object, but the specific guideline that has been breached
must be identified. The decision of the Parish Council is not final: it
is merely a consultee, alongside possibly many others, depending on the
type of the application. Neighbours are another class of consultee: all
have the right to submit their comments to the Planning Authority, which
is in this case is &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key decision to be made is whether or not the renewable energy
generated by these farms constitutes circumstances which are
sufficiently special to override the general principle that development
in the Green Belt is inappropriate. The relevant legislation is the
National Planning Policy Framework, supplemented by the government&amp;#8217;s
Planning Practice Guidance. Any decision about these applications, as in
the case of any other planning applications, will be decided in the
light of this planning legislation, not on the weight of local opinion
or on the value of renewable energy&amp;nbsp;generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parish Clerk, Knebworth: clerk@knebworthpc.org.uk or 01438&amp;nbsp;813795.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Planning Portal:&amp;nbsp;http://pa.north-herts.gov.uk/online-applications/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;: 01462 474000 or&amp;nbsp;service@north-herts.gov.uk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planning Practice Guidance:&amp;nbsp;http://planningguidance.planningportal.gov.uk/&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2014"></category></entry><entry><title>August Newsletter</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/august-newsletter-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-01T15:36:40+00:00</published><updated>2014-08-01T15:36:40+00:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2014-08-01:/august-newsletter-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;Local Plan, Fun Day, Parking, Village Trust, Norton&amp;nbsp;Green&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Letchworth&amp;nbsp;Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work of the council does not stop over the summer, although it does
slow down a bit. I have now attended sessions of each of the committees
on which I sit: Southern Rural, Overview and Scrutiny, as well the first
meeting of the full council in this, its fortieth year civic year. I
have also undertaken various sessions of training and induction, and am
now inducted into the mysteries of everything from governance, to
planning to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt;. The planning training was of great interest, as it is
very relevant for understanding the implications of the long-awaited
Local Plan. Although I am not a member of any of the committees at the
District Council concerned with planning, I take a close interest in all
applications which may affect Knebworth and continue to be a member of
the Planning Committee on the Parish&amp;nbsp;Council.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Knebworth Fun&amp;nbsp;Day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knebworth residents, being British, were not deterred by the wet weather
over the final weekend of the Knebworth Festival. The Fancy Dress
Competition took place with only slightly reduced (and slightly damp)
numbers. Rosemary Conybeare and I were called to judge the entries.
Years 2, 3 and 4, which had succeeded in forming the biggest group by
the tactic of combining their members into a single entry, were clear
winners from a strong field which had, inevitably, a World Cup inspired&amp;nbsp;theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Solar Farm&amp;nbsp;Application&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An application is currently being considered to build a solar farm on
Swangley&amp;#8217;s Farm, to the East of Knebworth. This will cover fifty acres
and have a peak generating capacity of around 10 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MW&lt;/span&gt;. There will,
undoubtedly be a great deal of discussion about this in the village
between now and October of November when a decision will have to be made
by the planning authority on whether to approve the application. Full
details of the application are available on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Planning&amp;nbsp;Portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;KPIG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hoped that the Knebworth Parking Initiative Group (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;KPIG&lt;/span&gt;) will
spring back into life in the next month or so. The first issue that we
will tackle is the lack of parking in Pondcroft Road and Milestone Road,
which have been particularly affected by commuter and other parking
displaced from Park Lane, Lytton Fields, Deanscroft and other areas to
the west of the railway line, as well as from the St Martins Road car
park. I have received a number of communications about various traffic
issues in the village, including Gun Lane, Station Approach, Park Lane
to the west of the A1(M), as well as Pondcroft Road/Milestone&amp;nbsp;Road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="quo"&gt;&amp;#8216;&lt;/span&gt;Knebworth High St.&amp;#8217; - i.e. the shopping area at the northern end of
London Road is a particular source of concern, both because traffic can
be dangerously fast, and because congestion is so bad that ambulances
and other emergency vehicles may be held up&amp;nbsp;unacceptably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an unused lot in Gun Road Gardens which may be suitable as a
place where some extra parking spaces can be found. This has been
suggested by some members of the Knebworth Community Group on Facebook.
If you are a Facebook user, I urge you to join the group, as it provides
a valuable forum to discuss issues affecting the&amp;nbsp;village.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Knebworth Village&amp;nbsp;Trust&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a District Councillor in Knebworth I am, &lt;em&gt;ex-officio&lt;/em&gt;, a trustee of
Knebworth Village Trust . This charity supports community groups based
within the parish of Knebworth. In our meeting on the 10th July we
decided to support a youth group run by the Trinity Church and the
(newly amalgamated) Knebworth Football Club. To find out whether your
community group could benefit from a grant from the Trust, please
contact the Hon. Secretary at info@knebworthtrust.com. The application
form for grants is available on their website:&amp;nbsp;www.knebworthtrust.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Norton Green&amp;nbsp;Subcommittee&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Norton Green Sub-Committee of the Planning and Environment Committee
of the Parish Council had its inaugural meeting on Independence Day, 4th
July. We had a detailed discussion about the legal ownership and status
of the common, which is a key&amp;nbsp;issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a very useful forum in which the interlocking issues affecting
the Common were identified. Members of the committee are: Rosemary
Conybeare, Rosemary Pateman, Karen Robinson, James Orme-Kirby and
myself, with the Clerk of the Parish Council, Claire Graham providing
much-needed&amp;nbsp;support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Parish Council would like to acquire title to the Common, which is
currently held by Stevenage Borough Council. Once this is achieved, it
is hoped that the management of this valuable resource, which includes a
Site of Special Scientific Interest, will be&amp;nbsp;improved.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2014"></category></entry></feed>