<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Steve Hemingway's Blog - 2015</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/feeds/2015.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://stevehemingway.github.io/</id><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>November</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/november.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-11-01T15:26:52+00:00</published><updated>2015-11-01T15:26:52+00:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2015-11-01:/november.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;November Newsletter&amp;nbsp;2015&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;modified: 2020-05-09
lang: &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EN&lt;/span&gt;-gb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NOVEMBER&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPDATE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Noise&amp;nbsp;Application&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; has introduced a Noise App to help deal with noise&amp;nbsp;nuisance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;North Hertfordshire District Council is using new technology to help deal with noise nuisance and has introduced a new Noise App. The app created by &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RH&lt;/span&gt; Environmental, allows residents with mobile devices to record incidents of nuisance noise and submit them to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; via the app. As unwanted noise is captured when it is actually happening, this makes it easier for residents to report problems and will allow the Council to more effectively investigate noise nuisance cases. Recorded audio files, which are sent securely, can also be shared with the Police and other agencies when tackling cases of anti-social&amp;nbsp;behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app can be downloaded free from the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; website: &lt;a href="http://www.north-herts.gov.uk/home/environmental-health/pollution/noise-app"&gt;http://www.north-herts.gov.uk/home/environmental-health/pollution/noise-app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Schedule of&amp;nbsp;Meetings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The schedule of meetings for North Hertfordshire District Council is available on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;’s website: &lt;a href="http://www.north-herts.gov.uk/home/council-and-democracy"&gt;http://www.north-herts.gov.uk/home/council-and-democracy&lt;/a&gt; Agendas are posted ahead of the meetings and while some items, such as the Budget process, follow an annual cycle, other topics are ad hoc – the Planning Control committee is a good example where individual applications that have been “called in” to the committee are discussed. The meetings are held at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;’s offices in Gernon Road, Letchworth, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SG6&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;3JF&lt;/span&gt; and are open for members of the public to observe; this includes the meetings of the Council’s&amp;nbsp;Cabinet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approval has been granted to purchase equipment which will allow council and committee meetings to be recorded and made available on the web as&amp;nbsp;podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2015"></category></entry><entry><title>Sept</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/sept-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-01T15:26:52+01:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2015-09-01:/sept-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;Sept Newsletter&amp;nbsp;2015&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SEPTEMBER&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPDATE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; – In the Summer &lt;strong&gt;time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; full council meetings are not scheduled during school holidays to make it easier for those with school age children to stand as councillors. There are some exceptions, with the Standards Committee meeting in August (see below), and planning applications continue to be considered because of strict deadlines on the time allowed for the council to process these. Generally, the routine work of the council via the officers and staff continues ensuring that services are not interrupted, while a range of extra activities, particularly aimed at children, are run at the leisure centres and other venues through the&amp;nbsp;district.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="post-office-opening" class="anchor"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Planning Code of&amp;nbsp;Conduct&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A draft of an updated Code of Conduct for Councillors was reviewed on 12&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; August by the Standards Committee of which I am a member. The code makes it clear that it is essential for all members to avoid any suggestion of bias in respect of local planning applications. Many decisions are taken by the Planning Control Committee, while in some circumstances the case may be decided by a full Council Meeting, or on rare occasions be referred to the Secretary of State for Communities and Local Government. This will not affect my ability, as District Councillor for Knebworth ward, to speak as member advocate for matters that affect&amp;nbsp;Knebworth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Three Houses Lane Solar Farm “Called&amp;nbsp;In”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Secretary of State for the Department for Communities and Local Government has “called in” the application for a solar farm in Three Houses Lane and confirmed that an inquiry will be held under Section 77 of the Town and Country Planning Act 1990. The situation is analogous to that of the application at Swangleys Lane and it is to be expected that the decision on the latter will be very significant for the Three Houses Lane application. Knebworth Parish Council is involved in the inquiry and neighbouring parish councils are also&amp;nbsp;involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Neighbourhood Plan Working Party – Any more&amp;nbsp;volunteers?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have one additional offer of help towards producing a Neighbourhood Plan for all (or part of) Knebworth Parish so we are still on track to convene an inaugural meeting in the Autumn. If you would like to get involved, especially if you have any professional expertise or involvement with Planning legislation, then please get in touch with me using the contact details&amp;nbsp;below.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2015"></category></entry><entry><title>August</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/august-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-01T15:26:52+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2015-08-01:/august-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;August Newsletter&amp;nbsp;2015&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AUGUST&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPDATE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; – Council Business&amp;nbsp;Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Council Meeting on 21 July covered a range of important issues, many of which will have an effect on North Hertfordshire residents long after the current Civic&amp;nbsp;Year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Council is preparing to respond to recent legislation to take into account Social Value in its tendering processes. This should make it easier for local businesses to sell goods and services to the&amp;nbsp;Council&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A report was accepted on the refurbishment of the North Herts Leisure Centre at Letchworth, costing in excess of &amp;pound;3 million, which should result in significantly improved facilities&amp;nbsp;there&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;#8216;Corporate Objectives&amp;#8217; which sets goals and priorities for the district until 2021, centred around &lt;em&gt;Promoting Sustainable Growth&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Working with Communities&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Living Within Our&amp;nbsp;Means&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports on projects such as Churchgate, Hitchin, and the North Herts Museum and Community Facility at Hitchin Town Hall, and from the Finance&amp;nbsp;Officers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Knebworth Post Office – New Look and Longer Opening&amp;nbsp;Hours&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was honoured to open officially the new-look Post Office in St Martin&amp;#8217;s Road, Knebworth. The branch has undergone a major refurbishment and upgrade of the old post office, which has remained largely unchanged from a time before I moved to Knebworth in 1985. It will now open for longer hours, until 6pm on weekday evenings and until 5.30pm on Saturdays, so giving more time for residents to pick up un-delivered parcels and generally use the services without the need to go further&amp;nbsp;afield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knebworth Post Office also now has a new Postmaster, with Mohammad Miah recently taking over from Nicola Low, who had held the position for the last thirty&amp;nbsp;years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Neighbourhood Plan Working Party – Interested in being&amp;nbsp;Involved?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a small number of volunteers offering to get involved in examining the feasibility of developing a Neighbourhood Plan for all (or part of) Knebworth Parish. If you would like to get involved, especially if you have any professional expertise or involvement with Planning legislation, then please get in touch with me using the contact details&amp;nbsp;below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is sufficient support I hope to convene an inaugural meeting in the Autumn and would expect to work extremely closely with the Parish Council on development of any Neighbourhood&amp;nbsp;Plan.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2015"></category></entry><entry><title>July</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/july-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-01T15:26:52+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2015-07-01:/july-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;July Newsletter&amp;nbsp;2015&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; - New Council&amp;nbsp;Appointment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first meeting has been held and the appointments of Chairs, Vice-Chairs and members of the various committees made. As well as being a member of the Southern Rural Committee, I have been appointed as the Vice-Chairman of the Overview and Scrutiny Committee. The function of this committee is to &amp;#8216;hold the executive to account&amp;#8217;. To this end we examine many performance statistics and call each portfolio holders to present a report to us once per year. We occasionally have meetings devoted to specific, usually large, projects that we consider require close scrutiny: e.g. last year a meeting was devoted to examining the redevelopment of Hitchin Town&amp;nbsp;Hall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Grants available through the Southern Rural&amp;nbsp;Committee&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; has limited funds, but does make grants to local organisations, as long as they are independent, not-for-profit and work for the benefit of the local community. Currently there is a Community Building Refurbishment Fund which has &amp;pound;15,000 available, and a Playground Fund and an Environmental Improvement Fund each with &amp;pound;10,000 available. With the exception of the Environmental Improvement Fund, community groups will be expected to raise at least 50% themselves. For further details see http://www.north-herts.gov.uk/home/community/grants or call 01462 474000 and ask for the Community Services&amp;nbsp;Team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant applications for Knebworth groups will be reviewed by the Southern Rural Committee, which meets four times a year. In our meeting on 11 June the committee approved &amp;pound;250 towards the cost of installing new pedestrian handrails on the steps to the footpath from New Close to Stevenage Road, and &amp;pound;200 towards the cost of developing the new Parish Council Website. Grant applications must be completed in good time before we meet, and may be submitted on paper or filled in online. The deadline for submissions for the next meeting in September is early&amp;nbsp;August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stevenage Borough Council – Consultation on Local Plan&amp;nbsp;2011-2031&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the development of the Stevenage Borough Local Plan 2011-2031, Stevenage Borough Council is undertaking a public consultation on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SBC&lt;/span&gt;’s preferred housing target for the Borough which is increased to 7,600 homes. Their preferred approach would roll-back the Green Belt within &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SBC&lt;/span&gt; and for needs beyond 2031 would wish to work with neighbouring councils to review the Green Boundary. The consultation on this aspect of the Emerging Local Plan runs from 22&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; June to 27 July 2015 and further information and how to submit a response can be found on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SBC&lt;/span&gt;’s website under Planning Policy:&amp;nbsp;http://www.stevenage.gov.uk/planning/planning-policy/&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2015"></category></entry><entry><title>June 2015</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/june-2015-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-01T15:26:52+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2015-06-01:/june-2015-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;June Newsletter&amp;nbsp;2015&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;June 2015&amp;nbsp;Newsletter&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Annual Meeting of the Parish on Wednesday the 6th of May, where
parking in Knebworth was one of the more burning issues under
discussion. Opinion in the village is sharply divided between those who
welcome the increased space available for shoppers, and those who worry
about availability of parking spaces for those who work in the village,
and those whose vehicles need to be near their place of work. I am in
discussion with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; to see if the balance between the needs of
residents and local businesses can be&amp;nbsp;improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parking as a wider issue in the village has not disappeared from the
agenda. I am trying to revive &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KPIG&lt;/span&gt;, the Knebworth Parking Initiative
Group, but I will have to wait until the portfolio holder for transport
is announced before I can make much more progress with this. Fairly
extensive changes have been made to parking in the village, and the
District is reluctant to deploy resources to change things even more,
unless there is compelling evidence that this will improve matters.
Clearly, the best outcome would be a new, large, free carpark near the
centre of the village, but reviving &lt;span class="caps"&gt;KPIG&lt;/span&gt; will not deliver&amp;nbsp;this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were no District or County elections this year for Knebworth.
However, there were a number of seats contested elsewhere in the
District, and your new Council will have a significantly different
composition to that of the civic year just ended. Responses to the
consultation on the emerging Local Plan will continue to be processed by
hard-pressed officers until August or September, but when the report is
ready I am sure that the Local Plan will once again hit the&amp;nbsp;headlines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Annual Meeting of the (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;) Council is scheduled take place on the
21st May. After this I will know which committees I am on, and who the
chairmen and vice-chairmen are of the various committees the make up the
District Council. I will be on the Southern Rural Committee, as this is
the one that deals with matters relating to the villages in the south of
the district, but I do not know yet which other committees (if any) I
shall be&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June will be a month of fêtes and festivals. Do not forget to put the
details of the Knebworth Festival in your diaries. Full details can be
found elsewhere in this issue. I will be attending most of the events
and look forward to seeing you at&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2015"></category></entry><entry><title>May</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/may-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-01T15:26:52+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2015-05-01:/may-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;May Newsletter&amp;nbsp;2015&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Review of my first year at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time you read this column I will have served as a member of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;
in the Knebworth Ward for (nearly) a whole year. It has been an eventful
one for matters that concern the District Council: a number of planning
applications for major brownfield developments, two solar farm
applications, the introduction of Knebworth&amp;#8217;s first Controlled Parking
Zone and the planned move of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Surgery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course the biggest issue of all is the ongoing, and &amp;#8216;emerging&amp;#8217; Local
Plan, which will continue emerging for a considerable time before it is
adopted. The current timetable envisages that this will happen in April
2017, two years&amp;#8217; from now, but the probability that this timetable will
slip must be significant, in the light of the rate of progress so&amp;nbsp;far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have done my best to represent the interests of all the residents of
the ward so far, and will continue to do so over the course of the next
civic year. I hope that my considerably increased experience of being a
District councillor will enable me to be no less effective than over the
previous twelve months, and hopefully a little bit more&amp;nbsp;effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large number of you have taken the opportunity to contact me, via
telephone, email and letter and I can assure you that I read every
communication personally, even if occasionally I may not have time to
send an individual response. There are, inevitably, many problems that
are not amenable to any easy solutions. A considerable part of my
postbag is connected to issues around road safety and parking. To this
end I am working towards re-starting the Knebworth Parking Initiative
Group in the coming year, a forum in which representatives from
Knebworwth village can have a dialogue with representatives of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many residents of Knebworth pointed out during the consultation on
the Local Plan, it is important that jobs are created locally if we are
to avoid having a community in which there is a good balance of local
employment and London commuters. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; is aware of the importance of
local economic activity and is looking for feedback on its Draft
Economic Development Strategy – ‘Productive North Herts’. This policy
aims to address issues related to growing new and existing businesses
across the District. The feedback from the consultation will form a
final strategy and action plan to help the economy grow and generate
employment opportunities locally. A draft Economic Development Strategy
has been published and feedback is encouraged via the Consultations area
of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; website, or by post to Economic Development, North
Hertfordshire District Council, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PO&lt;/span&gt; Box 480, Sale, M33 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;0DE&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2015"></category></entry><entry><title>April</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/april-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-01T15:26:52+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2015-04-01:/april-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;April Newsletter&amp;nbsp;2015&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;April 2015&amp;nbsp;Newsletter&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attended a meeting on 11 March with representatives of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; and
Stevenage Borough Council about the transfer of ownership and management
of Norton Green Common to Knebworth Parish Council. The discussion was
very constructive, and all parties confirmed that they could envisage no
major obstacles to the transfers taking place. The legal process will
take some time, and the Parish Council have yet to ratify that they wish
to take on this expanded role, but I believe that this meeting was a
milestone towards the goal of improving the Common as an important piece
of amenity land within the&amp;nbsp;Parish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Secretary of State for the Department for Communities and Local
Government has confirmed that an inquiry will be held under Section 77
of the Town and Country Planning Act 1990 into the application for
planning permission for the Swangleys Lane Solar Farm. Datchworth Parish
Council plan to submit evidence and make a representation to the
inquiry. They are looking for financial support from other Parish
Councils and other interested parties. The inquiry will examine the
appropriateness of developing this installation on this site in the
Green&amp;nbsp;Belt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a separate, but related matter, the planning application for the
solar generation facility at Three Houses Lane (ref. 14/02360/1) has
been amended and is being reviewed by &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;. The scale of the
installation has been reduced, to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;5MW&lt;/span&gt;, but it remains in the Green Belt.
Nicholas Pellett is leading the objectors to this application. Knebworth
Parish Council are opposed to the&amp;nbsp;application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Deakin Davies is looking for singers to appear in a video for the
Knebworth Festival, on 26 June. Lots of events and activities are
planned for the day, including a video featuring Knebworth singers, each
singing a line of &amp;#8216;Perfect Day&amp;#8217;, along the lines of the famous &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BBC&lt;/span&gt;
video. Contact Steve on 07508832581 for more&amp;nbsp;information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Planning Portal: via www.north-herts.gov.uk.&lt;br&gt;
Swangleys Lane Solar Farm: knebworthsolar.co.uk.&lt;br&gt;
Three Houses Lane Solar Farm: saveourherts.com.&lt;br&gt;
Knebworth Festival: facebook.com/Knebfest or Twitter @knebfest or&amp;nbsp;stevedeakindavies@hotmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2015"></category></entry><entry><title>March</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/march-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-03-01T15:26:52+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2015-03-01:/march-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;March Newsletter&amp;nbsp;2015&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;March&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Swangley&amp;#8217;s Farm Solar &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed solar farm at Swangley&amp;#8217;s Farm has been &amp;#8216;called in&amp;#8217;. It will
be referred to the Secretary of State for the Dept. for Communities and
Local Government under the Town and Country Planning Act 1990, Section
70. This was the recommendation of the planning officer of the District
Council. Documents relating to the application will now have to be
examined by the Planning Inspectorate. As of the time of writing, it is
not clear how long this process will&amp;nbsp;take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Council&amp;nbsp;Tax&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the District Council of the 12th February it was decided to increase
its proportion of Council tax by 1.9%, or &amp;pound;3.88 for a Band D property in
Knebworth. For such a property the contribution to the District Council
becomes &amp;pound;208.01. The balance of what you pay on your Council Tax is made
up of contributions to the Parish, the Police and the County, in order
of increasing cost, for the important services they provide to us&amp;nbsp;all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Welwyn Hatfield Local Plan&amp;nbsp;Consultation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welwyn Hatfield has started consulting on its Local Plan. Responses must
be submitted by the 20th March, so there is still time for you to
comment. For residents of Knebworth the proposal that is likely to be of
most interest is the potential development of the field between Gun
Meadow Avenue and Monread Lodge, although there are a number of
proposals along the B197 which will have an impact on&amp;nbsp;Knebworth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a Local Plan drop-in Consultation Event for the Welhat Plan on
7th March at Hatfield Hub, 56, Town Centre, Hatfield, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AL10&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;0JJ&lt;/span&gt;. For
further information contact the Welwyn Hatfield Planning Policy Team on
01707 357 000 or at&amp;nbsp;planningpolicy@welhat.gov.uk.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2015"></category></entry><entry><title>Feb</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/feb-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-02-01T15:26:52+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2015-02-01:/feb-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;February Newsletter&amp;nbsp;2015&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Future of the Knebworth &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Surgery&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herts County Council have now confirmed their intention of Herts County
Council that its intention is to enter into an agreement with General
Practice Investments, a developer, to re-develop the current library
site into a new Library, a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GP&lt;/span&gt; surgery and an associated pharmacy. This
is subject to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HCC&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GPI&lt;/span&gt; finding acceptable terms for the agreement.
Stephen McPartland, Richard Thake and I, together with Graham
Fothergill, representing both the Patient Participation Group, and the
Parish Council, had a meeting last year, with the practice manager where
we learned of this general intention. It is only this month (Jan) that
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HCC&lt;/span&gt; have confirmed their general&amp;nbsp;intention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sure that residents of the village will all welcome this
development, which should ensure that Knebworth has a modern,
fit-for-purpose, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GP&lt;/span&gt; surgery for many years to come. As many of you will
know, the library site has been the one that has been preferred by
Knebworth and Marymead General Practice for some years. I am very glad
that the process has moved on a stage so that we can look forward to a
new surgery opening, if everything goes well, in the next few&amp;nbsp;years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Norton Green&amp;nbsp;Common&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to report that Knebworth Parish Council has entered into a
Stewardship Agreement with Natural England for the management of Norton
Green Common. This agreement comes with over seven hundred pounds of
grants from Natural England to restore the Common to a good condition.
However the work needs to be done and the subcommittee are looking for
volunteers to do it! It is hoped that two days of will be organised in
the New Year when volunteers will be invited to work on clearance of the
Common. In addition to the grant from Natural England, now the Common is
registered it is eligible for payments from the Rural Payments Agency.
To find out more please contact the Clerk to the Parish&amp;nbsp;Council.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should mention that the Stewardship Agreement represents major
progress in the log hard slog that is the restoration of Norton Green
Common. It would not have been possible without tireless effort on the
part of Rosemary Pateman, Karen Robinson and the Parish&amp;nbsp;Clerk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Local&amp;nbsp;Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time you read this the Extraordinary Parish Meeting scheduled for
the 20th January will have been held. There is time to send your
response to the consultation to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;. Just email your comments to
localplans@north-herts.gov.uk or send via the post to Planning Policy,
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PO&lt;/span&gt; Box 480, Sale, M33 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;0DE&lt;/span&gt;. If you use email, please think about
copying in me and the Parish Council (clerk@knebworthpc.org.uk). The
deadline for submissions is the sixth of February, so don&amp;#8217;t&amp;nbsp;delay!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2015"></category></entry><entry><title>January</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/january-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-01-01T15:26:52+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2015-01-01:/january-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;January Newsletter&amp;nbsp;2015&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;JANUARY&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPDATE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Local Plan - Preferred Options&amp;nbsp;Consultation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The submissions made by members of the public to the Preferred Options Consultation, undertaken as part of the development of a new Local Plan, are now available on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;’s website. Every written response is available to read online - go to the page you get to by searching for &amp;#8216;&amp;#8220;Planning Policy Online Consultations&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;north-herts&amp;#8217;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;’s Grants&amp;nbsp;Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A report on Grants Policy is due to be discussed at the meeting of Cabinet on the 15th December. This will be reviewed by the Overview and Scrutiny Committee by the end of February&amp;nbsp;2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grants represent a modest, but important part of North Herts District Council’s cost base, and have to be reviewed just as we review all our spending commitments. Knebworth has to pay for the upkeep of its village hall, pavilion and recreation grounds through the precept levied by Knebworth Parish Council. Voters in the towns in the District have the equivalent expenditure paid for directly by the District Council, ie through the Council Tax paid by all householders in the District. Rural grants, to a degree, compensate villages for this anomaly. For this reason, the review of grants policy is very important to us, and I will continue to argue for a fair deal for the &amp;#8216;parished&amp;#8217;&amp;nbsp;areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to take a moment to reflect on the passing year. 2015 was a notable year with a number of major proposals put forward, most now decided, but others, most notably the development of the draft Local Plan, that will continue into 2016. Some of these could have significant impact on the village, and I hope you will continue to make your views known, and I will continue to try to reflect these in discussions with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; as your elected&amp;nbsp;councillor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be changes to your representation on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; as my fellow councillor, Alan Bardett, will be retiring at the end of his term in May 2016 when local elections will be held for some of the wards within &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; including, this time,&amp;nbsp;Knebworth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to the year ahead and wish you all a Happy New&amp;nbsp;Year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2015"></category></entry></feed>