<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Steve Hemingway's Blog - 2016</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/feeds/2016.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://stevehemingway.github.io/</id><updated>2016-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>"DECEMBER UPDATE"</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/december-update-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2016-12-01:/december-update-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Rail Services from Knebworth - Timetable Consultation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consultation has finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The consultation for the timetable for Govia Thameslink Railways is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;on-going but will close at 17:00 on 8th December. The proposals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;represent a significant change to the current service for Knebworth as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the stopping trains will now all come from …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Rail Services from Knebworth - Timetable Consultation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consultation has finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The consultation for the timetable for Govia Thameslink Railways is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;on-going but will close at 17:00 on 8th December. The proposals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;represent a significant change to the current service for Knebworth as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the stopping trains will now all come from Cambridge (rather than&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;alternately Cambridge and Peterborough), and become Thameslink services&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;going into St Pancras. Most significantly, this would mean Knebworth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;would not benefit from the fast services as present, although there are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;some suggestions that GTR have already had second thoughts about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evenings and Saturday services may be significantly reduced and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;proposals also suggest that Knebworth goes back to having only one train&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;per hour throughout the day on Sundays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our MP, Stephen McPartland, has made a formal response, available on his&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;website, and the Parish Council is actively preparing one, which should&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;be available on their website also. Full details on the proposals and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;how to respond are on the Great Northern Thameslink website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.thameslinkrailway.com/your-journey/timetable-consultation"&gt;http://www.thameslinkrailway.com/your-journey/timetable-consultation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;North Herts Leisure Centre and Council Offices Refurbishment&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work is progressing on refurbishing the North Herts Leisure Centre in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Letchworth. Much of this work was essential to keep the facility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;functioning safely, but a new pool and cafe are included in the works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This centre, which is operated by Stevenage Leisure Ltd on behalf of the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;council, produces revenue for the Council, which will go up under the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;agreed contractual arrangements once the work is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project to refurbish the Council Offices will soon be underway. It&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is expected that the work will start in the next month or so, and that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;staff will be relocated to other offices around the area. The work is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;being project managed by local firm, Wilmott Dixon. All staff will be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'decanted' from the existing District Council Offices to Town Lodge over&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the course of this month. Town Lodge is also in Gernon Road, but&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;opposite the Broadway Cinema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;NHDC Planning Portal&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The council's planning portal is being upgraded, to a more functional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;system. This will continue to be supplied by Idox PLC., the current&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;operator. A number of you have noticed how unsatisfactory the current&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;system is. I encourage you to try the new one and send your feed back to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;me or to NHDC at service@north-herts.gov.uk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you when I have&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;more details.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2016"></category></entry><entry><title>"NOVEMBER UPDATE"</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/november-update-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2016-11-01:/november-update-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;NHDC Local Plan – Public Consultation Period 19th October&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to end November &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The local public meeting ahead of the Parish Council meeting went ahead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;as planned on Wednesday 12th October. The hall was full, with many of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;those attending having to stand. The only occasion I can recall coming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;close to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;NHDC Local Plan – Public Consultation Period 19th October&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to end November &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The local public meeting ahead of the Parish Council meeting went ahead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;as planned on Wednesday 12th October. The hall was full, with many of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;those attending having to stand. The only occasion I can recall coming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;close to this level of attendance was the meeting to discuss the NHDC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preferred Options, in the fourth quarter of 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul Ward delivered an excellent summary of the Local Plan process. This&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;set the context and enabled members of the public to understand better&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;how they could participate effectively in the Local Plan consultation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;process. Both of your District Councillors were present, and did their&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;best to answer the questions addressed to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Parish Council, in its regular meeting after the public meeting,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;decided to allocate a budget to cover the cost of a planning consultant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to help it produce its response to the Local Plan consultation which&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;started on the 19th October and will run until the end of November. All&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;residents are encouraged to read the Plan, which will be available in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the Library, and online, and to submit their representations. A new&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;improved online system for recording representations will be accessible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via the District Council's website, or an email to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;localplan@north-herts.gov.uk, or a letter to Planning Policy, Local Plan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consultation, North Hertfordshire District Council, PO Box 480, M33 0DE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please ensure that you make it very clear which section of the Plan your&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;representation relates to. As I have explained previously, these&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;representations will be collated by NHDC and submitted to the Planning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspector ahead of the Public Enquiry, which is currently expected to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;take place in the second quarter of 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;NHDC Revised Grants Policy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The revised Grants Policy, now adopted, has reduced the total amount of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;money available for grants from the Council, and restricted the groups&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which are eligible. One of the big changes is that 'precepting bodies',&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;such as Parish Councils are not allowed to ask NHDC for grants. The&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;basis for this is that they already have the power to raise money from&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;local residents via Council Tax. Historically, parish councils have been&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a big recipient of NHDC Grants, so even with a reduced budget there is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;an opportunity for local community groups to obtain funding. The&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;grant-awarding committee which covers Knebworth, Codicote and other&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;southern parishes is Southern Rural. It still has a budget of around&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;pound;18,000 to spend by the end of the Civic Year, so now is the time to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;write your applications ready for the next committee meeting, which is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;on 1st December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that there is a separate committee which overseas capital grants&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for village halls, community halls and the like. This is the Community&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facilities Capital Projects Fund. The current four-year programme has&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;one million pounds to disburse for capital projects. Parish councils are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;permitted to apply for capital funding from this fund.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2016"></category></entry><entry><title>"OCTOBER UPDATE"</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/october-update-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2016-10-01:/october-update-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;NHDC Draft Local Plan&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction:&lt;/strong&gt; Last month I wrote about the development sites&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;allocated to Knebworth in the Local Plan. This month I will look at the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;broader context. Development sites are allocated very rarely. The last&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;time this happened in North Herts was in 1992. **Once the current Draft …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;NHDC Draft Local Plan&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction:&lt;/strong&gt; Last month I wrote about the development sites&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;allocated to Knebworth in the Local Plan. This month I will look at the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;broader context. Development sites are allocated very rarely. The last&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;time this happened in North Herts was in 1992. **Once the current Draft&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local Plan is approved the pattern of development in North Herts will be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;set for a generation.**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the draft plan is available on the NHDC website, but minor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;changes are still being made, so it is not possible to give any links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;here. Please check the website itself, and social media for the latest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implications of Local Plan for Knebworth:&lt;/strong&gt; There are several sites&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;proposed for Knebworth, see map, one in the centre of the village and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the rest for removal from the Green Belt, with dwelling estimates (area&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;based rule of thumb, not developer proposal) totalling 791, as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;

&lt;thead&gt;

&lt;tr class="header"&gt;

&lt;th align="left"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SHLAA Ref&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;

&lt;th align="left"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;

&lt;th align="left"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Site Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;

&lt;th align="left"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refined dwelling estimate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;

&lt;tr class="odd"&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;52&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Land at Deards End&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Green Belt&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;227&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr class="even"&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;335&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Land rear of Redwood, Deards End Lane&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Green Belt&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr class="odd"&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;53&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Land at Gypsy Lane&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Green Belt&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;229&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr class="even"&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;55&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Land North of Old Lane&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Green Belt&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;63&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr class="odd"&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;336&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Land east of Old Lane&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Green Belt&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;44&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr class="even"&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;57&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Land south of Swangley’s Lane&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Green Belt&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr class="odd"&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;58&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Land north of Watton Road&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Green Belt&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr class="even"&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;KB/m01&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Chas Lowe, London Road&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;PDL within village boundary&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;/tbody&gt;

&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why is this consultation different:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of you are probably suffering from 'consultation fatigue'. NHDC have consulted repeatedly on aspects of the local plan, which is not surprising since it was supposed to be ready by 2011. The most recent consultation, on the so-called &lt;em&gt;Preferred Options&lt;/em&gt; was in December 2014 and generated about eight and a half thousand responses from around the District, including a several hundred from Knebworth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This consultation is different because the responses will be examined by&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the Planning Inspector and will feed into the public enquiry where the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local Plan will finally be adopted (or not). NHDC will simply collate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the responses and pass them to the Inspector. Responses may be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;electronic or on paper, but not by telephone or in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that, if you submitted comments in response to previous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;consultations on the plan and believe that the updated plan does not&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fully address your concerns, you should submit your comments so that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;they will be received by the Planning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Soundness of Local Plan:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Planning Inspector will examine the Draft Local Plan to determine whether it is ‘sound’. A plan is sound if it is ‘&lt;em&gt;Positively prepared&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Justified&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Effective&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Consistent with national policy&lt;/em&gt;.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Positive Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This requires that the plan provides for enough&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;houses, business premises, infrastructure and community facilities. It&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;also requires that the plan is &lt;em&gt;sustainable&lt;/em&gt;, in the sense that it does&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;not cause irreversible damage to the environment or the well-being of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;future generations. Although developers are expected, in principle, to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pay for infrastructure, there is a requirement that the plan defines&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what infrastructure is needed. NHDC take the view that no account may be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;taken of 'Brexit' because it is too early to estimate its effects on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;housing numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Justified&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan is &lt;strong&gt;justified&lt;/strong&gt; only if it is based on compelling evidence and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that evidence is presented alongside the plan itself. The submitted&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;draft must be the best of all possible choices. Other choices for the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;plan, such as the suggestion that has been made for a 'New Garden City',&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;must be demonstrated to be inferior to the choices in the plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Effective&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan is &lt;strong&gt;effective&lt;/strong&gt; if it can be implemented within the available&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;timescale (before 2031). If the plan does not mesh with those of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;neighbouring authorities, or the infrastructure required to support it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cannot be built, the plan will fail the effectiveness test. The draft&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;submission plan calls for around 1,100 house completions a year to be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;delivered for the latter of the plan period. This is considerably more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;than North Herts has previously achieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Consistent with national policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan must be &lt;strong&gt;consistent with national policy&lt;/strong&gt;. A policy that many&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;local residents have commented on is the need to avoid changing Green&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belt boundaries, except under exceptional circumstances. Available&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sustainable brownfield sites in the District are limited and the vast&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bulk of land allocated for proposed housing is on sites which are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;currently in the Green Belt. There are many polices in the NPPF (and the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;associated Planning Practice Guidance website): I suggest that residents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;consider whether or not the Plan is consistent with the whole of the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NPPF, and not just the paragraph relating to the Green&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Timings:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NHDC Cabinet is scheduled to meet on 26th September to approve the current version of the plan to go forward to consultation. It will then become the 'draft submission plan'. If it is approved, the officers will prepare the material for consultation, and set up the consultation software on the NHDC website. Readers will be pleased to hear that new, improved software is being used this time, so the frustrations which the experienced trying to make representations on the Preferred Options draft &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be a thing of the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all goes according to plan the &lt;strong&gt;consultation period will run from the 19th October to the 30th November&lt;/strong&gt;. Again, this period will run over the Christmas holidays, and potentially means that some residents will have a very short window in which to read the documents and make their submissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the end of the consultation period, the submissions will be categorised by NHDC and submitted together with the Draft Plan and all other supporting material to the Planning Inspector in the first part of 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2016"></category></entry><entry><title>"SEPTEMBER UPDATE"</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/september-update-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2016-09-01:/september-update-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;NHDC Draft Local Plan&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update on Process:&lt;/strong&gt; Last month I highlighted the extraordinary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;meeting of the Council to endorse the proposed emerging (or draft) Local&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plan. It was the only topic on the agenda and the meeting heard public&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;participation from a number of groups, almost exclusively speaking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;against the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;NHDC Draft Local Plan&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update on Process:&lt;/strong&gt; Last month I highlighted the extraordinary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;meeting of the Council to endorse the proposed emerging (or draft) Local&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plan. It was the only topic on the agenda and the meeting heard public&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;participation from a number of groups, almost exclusively speaking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;against the proposals. The council heard a presentation from the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Executive Member for Planning, and then a prolonged debate involving&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;most of the council. The resolution to endorse the draft plan was&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;supported by 32 votes, with 12 voting against or abstaining (which&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;included me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implications of Local Plan for Knebworth:&lt;/strong&gt; There are several sites&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;proposed for Knebworth, one in the centre of the village and the rest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for removal from the Green Belt, with dwelling estimates (area based&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;rule of thumb, not developer proposal) totalling 791, as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;

&lt;thead&gt;

&lt;tr class="header"&gt;

&lt;th align="left"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SHLAA Ref&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;

&lt;th align="left"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;

&lt;th align="left"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Site Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;

&lt;th align="left"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refined dwelling estimate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;

&lt;tr class="odd"&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;52&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Land at Deards End&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Green Belt&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;227&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr class="even"&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;335&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Land rear of Redwood, Deards End Lane&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Green Belt&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr class="odd"&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;53&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Land at Gypsy Lane&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Green Belt&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;229&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr class="even"&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;55&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Land North of Old Lane&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Green Belt&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;63&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr class="odd"&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;336&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Land east of Old Lane&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Green Belt&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;44&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr class="even"&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;57&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Land south of Swangley’s Lane&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Green Belt&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr class="odd"&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;58&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Land north of Watton Road&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Green Belt&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr class="even"&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;KB/m01&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;Chas Lowe, London Road&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;PDL within village boundary&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;td align="left"&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;

&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;/tbody&gt;

&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A map of the sites is available, and you can find out more by searching&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for “draft emerging allocations Knebworth”, with information on the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parish Council and NHDC websites. The full detail of the Emerging Local&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plan may be obtained from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;www.north-herts.gov.uk/home/planning/planning-policy/emerging-local-plan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next Steps and Timings:&lt;/strong&gt; The next step is for a final decision by the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NHDC Cabinet to submit the plan for public consultation which, in this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;context, is collecting responses for review by the Planning Inspector,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;on behalf of the Secretary of State.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision by Cabinet will be taken at a meeting in September, so that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the statutory period of 6 weeks for the consultation will begin sometime&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;around mid October, so there is time to examine the proposals so that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you are ready to submit any comments once the consultation begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that, if you submitted comments in response to previous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;consultations on the plan, such as the Preferred Options consultation in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;December 2014, and believe that the updated plan does not fully address&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;your concerns, you should submit your comments again in October. This&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;time the comments will be examined by the Planning Inspector, on behalf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;of the Secretary of State, and not by the planning officers in NHDC, as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;part of his review of the whole plan. It is expected that formal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;submission to the Planning Inspector will happen in the first part of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2017 and approval of the plan will be some time after that, possibly not&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;until 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Joint Waste Collection and Street Cleaning Contract&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A contract for waste collection and street cleansing in the District is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;not the most exciting topic imaginable. However, it does account for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;around 45% of all North Herts District expenditure, so getting it wrong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;could have catastrophic consequences for the Council budget. It has been&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;decided to go out to tender jointly with East Herts as by doing this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there will be an elimination of duplication in management of the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;contract and should result in a reduction in unit costs. Before we can&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;do this the contract specifications for North and East Herts have to be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;brought into line: not least the termination date of our current&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;contracts, but also in some detailed aspects of waste and recycling. To&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;let the contract will therefore take quite some time, but the decision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;has now been made to move forward with the tender process.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2016"></category></entry><entry><title>"AUGUST UPDATE"</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/august-update-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2016-08-01:/august-update-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parking in Knebworth:&lt;/strong&gt; NHDC Councillor Julian Cunningham, the NHDC executive member with responsibility for parking policy, attended the Parish Council meeting in July. Cllr Cunningham ran through the Council’s current parking policy and confirmed that the underlying principles were unlikely to change in the new policy which is about …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parking in Knebworth:&lt;/strong&gt; NHDC Councillor Julian Cunningham, the NHDC executive member with responsibility for parking policy, attended the Parish Council meeting in July. Cllr Cunningham ran through the Council’s current parking policy and confirmed that the underlying principles were unlikely to change in the new policy which is about to be developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Residents at the meeting raised a number of issues, including hazardous parking on the east of London Road, south of Knebworth School, around the Gun Road/Gun Lane junction and along Hornbeam Spring, to mention just three of a considerable number of places of concern around the village.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gun Lane had been previously identified as likely to benefit from extending some of the existing double yellow lines. Our county councillor, Richard Thake was also present, which was useful as Herts CC and the Herts Constabulary are consultees in matters of road safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NHDC Draft Local Plan:&lt;/strong&gt; As I write there is a week to go before an extraordinary meeting of the Council to consider a draft Local Plan. If that Council meeting endorses the plan, it will be taken forward the NHDC Cabinet meeting in September as, under the council’s constitution, Cabinet has the ultimate responsibility for approving the final draft for submission for examination by the government appointed Planning Inspectorate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming that Cabinet approve the plan, public consultation will commence shortly thereafter, with a statutory six-week period. At this stage of the process the Council collates responses and submits them for examination by the Inspector, together with all associated supporting information relating to the draft plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find detailed information on the NHDC website at this address: www.north-herts.gov.uk/home/planning/planning-policy/emerging-local-plan/proposed-submission-local-plan-2011-2031&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flooding in Knebworth Cemetery:&lt;/strong&gt; Officers from Herts CC and NHDC, Stephen McPartland MP and I inspected Knebworth cemetery (off Wadnall Way), part of which has been subject to periodic flooding, to understand what practical solutions to improving the drainage can be found. Herts CC, who are the responsible body for flood plans, explained that it was important that any changes did not increase the possibility of flooding further into the village, and thereby put properties at risk, and undertook to provide a summary of the issues. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2016"></category></entry><entry><title>"JULY UPDATE"</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/july-update-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2016-07-01:/july-update-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NHDC Grants Policy:&lt;/strong&gt; NHDC awards grants every year of around half a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;million pounds. The existing policy for determining eligibility for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;grants largely dates back to 2002 and was no longer fit for purpose, and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a revised grants policy was approved by the NHDC Cabinet on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; June. The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NHDC Grants Policy:&lt;/strong&gt; NHDC awards grants every year of around half a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;million pounds. The existing policy for determining eligibility for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;grants largely dates back to 2002 and was no longer fit for purpose, and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a revised grants policy was approved by the NHDC Cabinet on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; June. The revised policy puts some more stringent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;requirements on bodies applying for grants, with recommendations that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘precepting bodies' (i.e. parish councils) be no longer eligible to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;apply for grants, no more than grant will be awarded to a body in any&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;one year, and no grant will be given where a body has been awarded a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;grant in two consecutive years. Southern Rural, along with the other&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;area committees, will suffer an approximately 50% drop in the funds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;available for grants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is recognized that parishes such as Knebworth may have difficulty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;raising funds for capital projects so a new capital funding scheme has&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;been proposed which is designed to help both rural and urban capital&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;projects. The idea is that village and community halls can be helped out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;when they have larger capital spending needs. The proposal is to make&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;available a quarter of a million pounds annually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parking in Knebworth – meeting on 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; July:&lt;/strong&gt; NHDC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Councillor Julian Cunningham will be attending the Parish Council&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;meeting on 13 July at 8pm. He is the Executive Member (i.e. member of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NHDC Cabinet) with responsibility for parking policy. An hour at the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;beginning of the meeting has been set aside to discuss parking problems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in the village.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NHDC Draft Local Plan – meeting on 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; July:&lt;/strong&gt; On 20th&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;July there will be an extraordinary meeting of the Council to approve a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;draft Local Plan; as with other Council meetings this meeting is open to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the public. The plan will be scrutinized by a planning inspector at a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;public enquiry, probably in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flooding in Knebworth Cemetery:&lt;/strong&gt; Stephen McPartland MP, officers from&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herts CC and NHDC and I will be inspecting Knebworth cemetery (off&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wadnall Way), part of which has been subject to periodic flooding, to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;understand what practical solutions to improving the drainage can be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knebworth Neighbourhood Plan Area:&lt;/strong&gt; At its meeting on 14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June the NHDC Cabinet approved the Neighbourhood Plan Area for Knebworth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;as being the whole of the Parish. See the Parish Council article in this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;issue for further information about the Neighbourhood Plan.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2016"></category></entry><entry><title>"JUNE UPDATE"</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/june-update-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2016-06-01:/june-update-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Welcome to Steve Deakin-Davies, New NHDC Councillor for Knebworth&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the local election for one of the NHDC seats for Knebworth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ward in May, Steve Deakin-Davies was elected as a councillor. Steve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;enjoys living in Knebworth together with his partner and children, and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;has lived here for over 14 years …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Welcome to Steve Deakin-Davies, New NHDC Councillor for Knebworth&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the local election for one of the NHDC seats for Knebworth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ward in May, Steve Deakin-Davies was elected as a councillor. Steve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;enjoys living in Knebworth together with his partner and children, and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;has lived here for over 14 years having lived nearby previously for a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;similar length of time. Steve had previously been a Parish Councillor,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and has been involved in a wide range of community activities, most&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;recently with the Knebworth Festival when he ran a video and live&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;performance night showcasing local talent. Steve is interested in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;helping young people get a start in life as entrepreneurs, and works as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a lecturer and mentor at the University of Hertfordshire, helping set up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and develop a range of businesses. Steve also has an interest in health&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;matters, and previously work as a nurse at the Lister Hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;NHDC New Civic Year&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The civic year for NHDC runs from May, following the local elections in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knebworth ward and a number of other NHDC seats. The new council will&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;therefore have a different composition to the year just ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Annual Meeting of the NHDC Council on 19th May is the first meeting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;of the new year, and includes appointment onto the various committees&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that make up the District Council, and the chairs and vice-chairs of the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;committee. Both Steve Deakin-Davies and I will be on the Southern Rural&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Committee, as this is the one that deals with matters relating to the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;villages in the south of the district, and will advise on which other(s)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we will individually be on next month once the annual meeting has been&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;held.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June will be a month with many activities, including the Knebworth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Festival, and I am looking forward to going along to some of the events&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and will no doubt see some of you there.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2016"></category></entry><entry><title>"MAY UPDATE"</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/may-update-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2016-05-01:/may-update-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;NHDC Emerging Local Plan&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of producing the new Local Plan for the North Herts District&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is progressing. The record number of over 8,000 responses to the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preferred Options consultation last year has meant that, despite long&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hours of work from the Planning Policy Officers, the consideration of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;NHDC Emerging Local Plan&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of producing the new Local Plan for the North Herts District&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is progressing. The record number of over 8,000 responses to the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preferred Options consultation last year has meant that, despite long&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hours of work from the Planning Policy Officers, the consideration of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the comments will take until the summer and Consultation on the Proposed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submission to the Secretary of State will follow thereafter. The formal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;submission is expected to be made in March 2017 according to the current&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;timetable (Local Development Scheme).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been some suggestions that there will be a substantial&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;increase in the housing allocation numbers in the Emerging Local Plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the case that recent revised ONS figures suggest an increase, and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it is also the case that the National Planning Policy Framework suggests&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that sites are identified in excess of the actual need to allow for some&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;flexibility. It is expected that there will be more clarity on this in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the next weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the Consultation, a number of new sites have been put forward&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for review by the officers. They are in the process of being evaluated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;against exactly the same criteria that were used to select the sites&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that were included in the Preferred Options consultation. In Knebworth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;itself, three additional sites have been put forward for consideration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for inclusion in the Local Plan – see&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.north-herts.gov.uk/planning/planning-policy/local-plan-emerging-policy/draft-local-plan-2011-2031/local-plan-preferred&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(click on the text which reads "[New sites 2015 (additional sites&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;submitted&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;since 2013)](http://www.north-herts.gov.uk/sites/northherts-cms/files/Composite%20document%202.pdf)").&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All are currently in the Green Belt, so this is, essentially, a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;suggestion that they be taken out of the Green Belt. On the document
titled "NHDC Local Plan - New Sites 2015" these sites are numbered 334,
335 and 336. They are Cnebba's Field, Old Knebworth, the land to the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;rear of Redwoods in Deards End Lane, and land east of Old Knebworth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;lane. The three sites would comprise 79 potential dwellings in all, but&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; if the sites are found to have met the criteria for inclusion. No&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;decision on this have yet been made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Knebworth GP Surgery&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am regularly asked about the status of the new GP surgery. As I&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;understand it, a planning application is due to be made this month,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;assuming that the new arrangements for the Library are confirmed by HCC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in a cabinet meeting scheduled for 28&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; April. I understand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the impatience that people feel about this, but emphasise that NHDC is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;not responsible for the delays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Thank you to retiring Councillor Alan Bardett&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After serving as a District Councillor for over 14 years, Alan Bardett&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;has decided to retire and therefore not seek re-election in this year’s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;elections. I would like to offer my great thanks to Alan for showing me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the ropes and giving me advice when I was a new councillor only two&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;years ago, as well as for all his efforts on behalf of our village over&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the many years of service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Annual Parish Meeting – Wednesday, 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; May&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be attending the Annual Parish Meeting on 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see the article from the Parish Council for more details.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2016"></category></entry><entry><title>"March UPDATE"</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/march-update-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2016-03-01:/march-update-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Council Tax for 2016-17&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;– NHDC Budget&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the full North Herts District Council meeting on 11 Feb the Executive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Member for Finance, Terry Hone, presented his budget for next year (Apr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016 – Mar 2017) for the District, later than usual as central&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;government took a long while to decide on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Council Tax for 2016-17&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;– NHDC Budget&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the full North Herts District Council meeting on 11 Feb the Executive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Member for Finance, Terry Hone, presented his budget for next year (Apr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016 – Mar 2017) for the District, later than usual as central&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;government took a long while to decide on the financial settlement for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;local councils. The settlement for NHDC is &amp;pound;871,000 of Revenue Support&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant for next year and after that zero, i.e. from April 2017 NHDC’s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;expenditure (net of income received) has to be provided 100% by local&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Council Tax Payers. NHDC is one of only 15 local authorities in England&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to be facing a zero revenue support grant, which reflects the relative&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;prosperity of the residents of North Herts. However, as a result of the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;response to the consultation on the financial settlement to local&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;authorities’ additional central government funding has been provided. A&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so-called Transition Grant has been awarded to NHDC to ease the move to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;zero RSG. This amounts to &amp;pound;285,000 in total and will be received over&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the next two civic years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The budget for 2016/17 results in the District component of Council Tax&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;being set at the equivalent of &amp;pound;211.96 for a Band D property, an&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;increase of 1.9% over the current year. For a Band D property, the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;charge for the cost of services provided by NHDC is therefore 58p per&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;day, or just over &amp;pound;4 per week; the increase is only 1.1p per day. The&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;recommendation to adopt the budget received all party support at the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;council meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, your Council Tax bill includes elements to fund services&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;provided by the County Council, the Police and the Parish Council, so&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;your total Council Tax bill will be considerably greater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt;District-Wide Survey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NHDC seeks to understand people’s satisfaction with the Council and its&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;services. A North Herts District Wide Survey is a consultation exercise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that takes place every two years. The survey consists of approximately&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1,000 residents from across North Hertfordshire who are consulted via&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;telephone interviews. These interviews are carried out by independent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;consultants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most recent survey was carried out in October and November last&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;year. The report from this survey is expected to be presented to Cabinet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;next month, and will be available on the website from about mid-March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the District-Wide Survey new members of the Citizen’s Panel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;are selected. This is a group of residents who are regularly contacted&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;about their views on Council performance, so that trends in satisfaction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;levels can be tracked on a more frequent basis than every two years.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2016"></category></entry><entry><title>"FEBRUARY UPDATE"</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/february-update-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2016-02-01:/february-update-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Flooding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;December and January have seen extremely heavy rain falling, seemingly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;without respite. The consequences are that the gullies around the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;village have struggled to take the flow, and we have come perilously&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;close to the flooding that was experienced in Orchard Way/Broom Grove a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;couple of years ago …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Flooding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;December and January have seen extremely heavy rain falling, seemingly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;without respite. The consequences are that the gullies around the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;village have struggled to take the flow, and we have come perilously&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;close to the flooding that was experienced in Orchard Way/Broom Grove a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;couple of years ago. Unfortunately a number of the graves in the NHDC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cemetery in Wadnall Way have been temporarily submerged. NHDC is aware&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;of the problem and have taken steps to inspect the site with, as yet, no&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;solution proposed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Council Tax&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NHDC financial team are busy preparing a final budget for 2016-17.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of uncertainties around the amount of money available&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from central taxation: the so called ‘Revenue Support Grant’. A number&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;of decisions around this are scheduled to be made at Cabinet this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is likely that more efficiency savings will be made.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Syrian Refugees&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NHDC Cabinet decided in December that Syrian refugees Hertfordshire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;will be welcomed under the terms of a resettlement scheme recommended by&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the Home Office if they decide to come to North Herts. Full council&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;voted, in November, to indicate to the Home Office that the District&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;would be interested in helping fifty refugees to resettle here, in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;family groups, over the next five years, a total of ten individuals per&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;year, possibly three or four families. The national scheme includes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;financial assistance to local authorities prepared to welcome refugees,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;who will be transported to the UK directly from camps in Syria or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;immediately neighbouring countries.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2016"></category></entry></feed>