<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Steve Hemingway's Blog - 2018</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/feeds/2018.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://stevehemingway.github.io/</id><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>KCC Christmas Concert</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/kcc-christmas-concert-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-12-09T15:33:55+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2018-12-09:/kcc-christmas-concert-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;My Latest&amp;nbsp;Post&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Everyone enjoyed himself at the wonderful concert laid on by Knebworth Community Chorus this Saturday. The Village Hall was full to bursting, and many mince pies were consumed. A fair volume of mulled wine was drunk&amp;nbsp;too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The children of St Michael&amp;#8217;s,  Woolmer Green School put on a wonderful performance of singing and playing their instruments: violins and&amp;nbsp;flutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merry&amp;nbsp;Christmas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve.  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2018"></category><category term='"Politics"'></category><category term='"Knebworth"'></category><category term='"social media"'></category></entry><entry><title>More NHDC grants awarded</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/more-nhdc-grants-awarded-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-12-09T13:08:14+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2018-12-09:/more-nhdc-grants-awarded-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; awards grants to Royston Bowls&amp;nbsp;Club&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Royston Bowls Club received £1,000 towards the purchase of a machine to de-thatch the green in order to help reduce disease and improve the playing&amp;nbsp;surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The club’s Steve Kilford said: “Royston Bowls Club would like to thank the council for awarding us a grant of £1,000, this will go some way towards the purchase of a de-thatching&amp;nbsp;machine.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Royston Historical Pageant was awarded a grant of £500 to assist with the costs of putting on a large historical event on Therfield Heath in July&amp;nbsp;2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The funding will be used to assist with publicity and advertising costs and to pay for re-enactment groups to&amp;nbsp;attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Councillor Sarah Dingley, pageant co-ordinator, said: “Grateful thanks to the Royston Area Committee for the grant awarded to Royston Historical&amp;nbsp;Pageant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It will help us to create a memorable event for the whole&amp;nbsp;community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, the Royston Choral Society was awarded a grant of £750 to assist with the costs of putting on a community concert. The funding will go towards the publicity and equipment hire for their performance of Bach’s St John Passion at Royston’s parish church on April 6,&amp;nbsp;2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Royston Choral Society has been putting on concerts for the people of Royston since 1974 and the event is part of the society’s commitment to put on 4 concerts&amp;nbsp;annually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huw Jenkins, Chairman of the Royston Choral Society said: “The Royston Choral Society has been a community unauditioned choir since 1974. We recently performed Britten’s War Requiem to high acclaim and will continue to rise to the challenges set by the musical director, Andrew O’Brien, with the performance of Bach’s St John Passion in the&amp;nbsp;spring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are most grateful for this grant from North Herts District Council as it will support the Royston Choral Society in its commitment to provide ‘Fine music made&amp;nbsp;locally’.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Councillor Tony Hunter, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;’s chairman of the Royston Committee, said: “We are pleased to be able support these projects in Royston. We look forward to seeing how the projects develop and progress in the&amp;nbsp;future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grants are subject to completion of the necessary&amp;nbsp;formalities.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2018"></category><category term='"Politics"'></category><category term='"NHDC"'></category></entry><entry><title>Self-build and Custom Build Register</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/self-build-and-custom-build-register-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2018-03-27:/self-build-and-custom-build-register-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;Self-build and Custom Build&amp;nbsp;Register&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You can use &lt;a href="https://www.north-herts.gov.uk/home/planning/planning-policy/self-build-and-custom-build-register"&gt;The North Herts Self Build and Custom Build Register&lt;/a&gt;   to register yourself as wanting a plot in the District for a self-build&amp;nbsp;home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New rules came into effect on 31 October 2016 which amended the Self-build and Custom Housebuilding Act 2015 and implemented Chapter 2 of the Housing and Planning Act 2016 which sets out provisions to support self-build and custom&amp;nbsp;housebuilding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that the second and final part of the Right to Build, placing a duty on relevant authorities to make land available to meet the demand on their self-build and custom housebuilding registers, has now come into force and the Right to Build is now fully&amp;nbsp;implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The legislation requires ‘relevant authorities’ to keep a register of individuals and associations of individuals who are seeking to acquire serviced plots of land in the authority’s area and to have regard to that register when carrying out their functions. Unless exempt, they also have a legal duty to grant sufficient ‘development permissions’ to meet the demand for self-build and custom housebuilding in their&amp;nbsp;area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regulation 2 (Time for compliance with duty to grant planning permission) specifies three years as the period within which the required number of development permissions relating to a ‘base period’ must be granted to satisfy the duty (as set out in the Housing and Planning Act&amp;nbsp;2016).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2018"></category><category term='"Politics"'></category><category term='"Knebworth"'></category><category term='"social media"'></category></entry><entry><title>Consultation: unauthorized developments and encampments</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/consultation-unauthorized-developments-and-encampments-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2018-03-01:/consultation-unauthorized-developments-and-encampments-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you may know, the Government have recently issued a consultation on powers for dealing with unauthorised developments and encampments. The consultation document can be found &lt;a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/697354/Consultation_-_unauthorised_encampments.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions include:
1.      What evidence is there of unauthorised development and encampments in your community, and what issues does this raise for the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you may know, the Government have recently issued a consultation on powers for dealing with unauthorised developments and encampments. The consultation document can be found &lt;a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/697354/Consultation_-_unauthorised_encampments.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions include:
1.      What evidence is there of unauthorised development and encampments in your community, and what issues does this raise for the local&amp;nbsp;community?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We would like to invite evidence of unauthorised encampments which have occurred in the last 2 years, as follows:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the number of instances where trespassers have occupied land without authorisation, including the location and scale of the&amp;nbsp;encampment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;whether the land in a) required cleaning or repair once the encampment had left, and if so, what was the&amp;nbsp;cost?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how was each unauthorised encampment encouraged to leave, how long did it take, and was the local authority able to move them on; or did the police became&amp;nbsp;involved?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you think that the existing powers made available to local authorities to remove unauthorised campers from land are&amp;nbsp;effective?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you think local authorities could improve their use of existing&amp;nbsp;powers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What other powers may help local authorities deal with unauthorised&amp;nbsp;encampments?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you consider that the current powers for police to direct trespassers to leave land are&amp;nbsp;effective?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would any new or revised powers that enable police to direct trespassers to leave land make it easier to deal with unauthorised&amp;nbsp;encampments?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you consider that the Government should consider criminalising unauthorised encampments, in addition to the offence of aggravated trespass? If so, how should a new offence differ, and what actions and circumstances should it apply&amp;nbsp;to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What barriers are there to the greater use of injunctions by local authorities, where appropriate, and how might they be&amp;nbsp;overcome?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you have any suggestions or examples of how local authorities, the police, the courts and communities can work together more successfully to improve community relations and address issues raised by unauthorised&amp;nbsp;encampments?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there ways in which court processes might be modified in a proportionate way to ensure unauthorised encampments can be addressed more&amp;nbsp;quickly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your view, what would the advantages and disadvantages be of extending the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IPO&lt;/span&gt; process to open land? Are you aware of any specific barriers which prevent the effective use of current planning enforcement&amp;nbsp;powers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are aware of any specific barriers to effective enforcement, are there any resourcing or administrative arrangements that can help overcome&amp;nbsp;them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you aware of any specific barriers which prevent the effective use of temporary stop notices? If so, do you have a view on how these barriers can be&amp;nbsp;overcome?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you think the existing enforcement notice appeals process can be improved or&amp;nbsp;streamlined?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can Government make existing guidance more effective in informing and changing&amp;nbsp;behaviour?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If future guidance was issued as statutory guidance, would this help in taking action against unauthorised development and&amp;nbsp;encampments?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there any specific barriers to the provision of more authorised permanent and transit sites? If so, is there any action that the Government could take to help overcome those&amp;nbsp;barriers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What impact would extending local authority, police or land owner powers have on children and families and other groups with protected characteristics that public authorities must, in the exercise of its functions, have due regard to under their Public Sector Equality&amp;nbsp;Duty?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you expect that extending the powers referred to above would have a positive or negative impact on the health or educational outcomes of Gypsy, Roma and Traveller communities? If so, do you have any evidence to support this view, and/or suggestions for what could be done to mitigate or prevent any negative&amp;nbsp;impacts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you have any other comments to make on the issue of unauthorized development and encampments not specifically addressed by any of the questions&amp;nbsp;above?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="2018"></category><category term='"Consultations"'></category></entry><entry><title>Steve Hemingway’s Corner of the World Wide Web</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/steve-hemingways-corner-of-the-world-wide-web-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2018-02-18:/steve-hemingways-corner-of-the-world-wide-web-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;About this&amp;nbsp;website&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Note that I was defeated in the District Council elections in May 2017. I
continue to be active in Knebworth and hope that I may serve the electors again
one day. However, I no longer write a column in the Parish News which makes this
kind of website rather inconvenient to maintain. I plan to write the odd post in
a website called &lt;a href="https://minds.com"&gt;minds.com&lt;/a&gt;. You can find my contributions
at &lt;a href="https://www.minds.com/2chj9"&gt;this address&lt;/a&gt;. At the moment there is not much
to see. I hope this will change in future. Freed from the constraints of writing
material relevant to voters in Knebworth, I plan to paint on a broader canvas,
including on the topic of economic policy, something I have had an interest in
for a long&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to load up my regular columns for Knebworth Parish News onto this website. I occasionally post things here, but for anything I have to say that can be fitted into 280 characters, I tend to use &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SteveKnebworth"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website does not use cookies, but even if it did you should not be worried about&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t keep any information about you, although I am registered with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ICO&lt;/span&gt;, just in&amp;nbsp;case.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2018"></category><category term='"Politics"'></category><category term='"North Herts"'></category><category term='"About"'></category></entry><entry><title>The Station Pub planning application - decision time?</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/the-station-pub-planning-application-decision-time-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-29T14:46:26+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2018-01-29:/the-station-pub-planning-application-decision-time-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Station&amp;nbsp;Pub&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The long-awaited application for redevelopment of the Station Pub site (Planning Reference 17/01622/1) is likely to come before the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Planning Control Committee this month, on the 15th February, probably in the Spirella Building in Letchworth. If you plan to attend, please check on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC …&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Station&amp;nbsp;Pub&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The long-awaited application for redevelopment of the Station Pub site (Planning Reference 17/01622/1) is likely to come before the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Planning Control Committee this month, on the 15th February, probably in the Spirella Building in Letchworth. If you plan to attend, please check on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; website for confirmation that the application is on the agenda. The start time of the meeting will be 7:30pm, but this application will be one of potentially many all of which will be decided at this&amp;nbsp;meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has taken a long time for the application to come before the Committee. I do not know why this is, but a frequent reason is because the negotiations between the developer and the officers for Section 106 Contributions have been drawn&amp;nbsp;out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When an application comes before the Committee the members will have visited the site and read all the associated paperwork, including the objections and plans. Particular attention will be given to the responses from the statutory consultees, especially Herts Highways and Knebworth Parish Council. Committee members will rely on the report of the planning officer for guidance on which policies are relevant and to what extent the application complies with them. This is the job of the committee, to decide whether or not the officer has, in his professional capacity, missed any valid planning ground (i.e. breach of policy) on which the application might be&amp;nbsp;refused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meeting, the planning officer involved will introduce his report and summarize the main findings, including his recommendation. If this is to refuse the application, it is very unlikely the Committee will go against his recommendation. However, if the recommendation is to grant, it will need to have some fairly compelling reasons why. The objectors will have to provide these compelling reasons, all in a speech lasting no longer than five&amp;nbsp;minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the local ward member I, or my fellow councillor, may speak in support of the objector for a further five minutes. The applicant is also allowed to speak for this amount of time, to rebut any of the arguments put forward by the objectors. After the speeches, the committee may ask  of the speakers about their&amp;nbsp;comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The committee will then debate the application until one of them proposes a motion to refuse the application or to grant it, possibly with additional conditions to those recommended in the report. If the motion is to grant, and the vote is passed, the applicant is free to proceed with construction. No appeal is possible in this&amp;nbsp;event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the motion is to refuse, and it is passed, the applicant has up to six months to appeal to the Planning Inspector. Or he has the option to submit a new application, presumably somewhat amended to take account of the reason for&amp;nbsp;refusal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members of the Planning Control Committee are not professional planners. They are elected District Council members. They are heavily dependent on guidance from planning professionals to make their decisions. Planning law is complex, and even the council&amp;#8217;s own planning officers sometimes need to call in specialist advice. However, they are attuned to local need and I am sure they will arrive at the right decision as long as they are in possession of all the arguments for and against the&amp;nbsp;application. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2018"></category><category term='"Politics"'></category><category term='"Knebworth"'></category><category term='"social media"'></category></entry><entry><title>Contacting Me</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/contacting-me.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2018-01-01:/contacting-me.html</id><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Contact&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact me just send an email to&amp;nbsp;steve@stevehemingway.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are willing to help re-elect me or other Conservative Party candidates in the area, please click &lt;a href="http://eepurl.com/cIvGPj"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2018"></category></entry><entry><title>January Parish News Article</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/january-parish-news-article-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-30T16:40:07+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2017-12-30:/january-parish-news-article-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Garden Waste&amp;nbsp;Bins&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of you will be aware of the new charging regime for garden waste bins being introduced this year. Removal of household waste remains a statutory obligation for the Council, and not one that it may charge for. This includes food waste which will be collected weekly …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Garden Waste&amp;nbsp;Bins&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of you will be aware of the new charging regime for garden waste bins being introduced this year. Removal of household waste remains a statutory obligation for the Council, and not one that it may charge for. This includes food waste which will be collected weekly from food caddies to be provided. While this will mean an additional container, the alternative would be to allow food waste to be put in the ‘residual waste’ (i.e. purple) bins. Although this would have saved money, it was considered a worse option from an environmental point of view and was rejected. The new caddies will be 23l in capacity, enough for a week, so considerably bigger than the old ones, which are at most&amp;nbsp;4l.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Householders who pay for garden waste bins will be able to continue to use them for food waste, but with a fortnightly collection, and leave their new caddy unused. Bonfires are allowed, provided they do not create a nuisance, which can reduce garden waste; householders may have more than one brown bin (at &amp;pound;40 pa each) or can&amp;nbsp;share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Forthcoming &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;meetings&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Cabinet on 21st January is expected to review the revenue budget and capital spending programme for the next civic year; these items will be referred to full Council on 8 February&amp;nbsp;2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both these meetings are open to members of the public. Please check the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; website for details of the location for each meeting as the District Council offices in Gernon Road are currently out of action. The office refurbishment is expected to be finished by the end of the first&amp;nbsp;quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Enhanced provision for the&amp;nbsp;homeless&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; remains responsible for homelessness, even though it no longer owns any housing stock having transferred its former stock to North Herts Homes in&amp;nbsp;2004.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although homelessness in North Herts is very low (at the last count under five families), for those affected it can be devastating, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; has a number of housing officers who help avoid homelessness and provide assistance to those affected. Currently, in some cases, families can end up being housed in temporary accommodation in adjacent areas. The Homelessness Reduction Act 2017, which comes into force in April 2018, is likely to increase the load on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; who are actively considering establishing a Housing Company that will own residential accommodation to be used for temporary&amp;nbsp;accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to take this opportunity to wish you all a Happy New Year and my best wishes for&amp;nbsp;2018.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2018"></category><category term='"Politics"'></category><category term='"Knebworth"'></category><category term='"social media"'></category></entry></feed>