<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Steve Hemingway's Blog - "consultation"</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/feeds/consultation.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://stevehemingway.github.io/</id><updated>2017-06-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>CAA consultation</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/caa-consultation-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-14T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-06-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2017-06-14:/caa-consultation-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CAA&lt;/span&gt; Consultation on decision making&amp;nbsp;process&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I received the following email letter today, and I thought it would be useful to share it with local residents. Luton airport is an important 
local employer, as well as a very important public transport hub for us all, but it does create some problems. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CAA&lt;/span&gt; are keen to hear your&amp;nbsp;views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Letter from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CAA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Cllr&amp;nbsp;Hemingway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Civil Aviation Authority (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CAA&lt;/span&gt;) is currently consulting on a new decision making process for all future airspace&amp;nbsp;changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This consultation ends on June&amp;nbsp;30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules, regulations and technology that underpin the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt;’s airspace and network of flight paths have remained largely unchanged despite the growing increase in demand for air travel in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UK&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, London Luton’s ability to modify and improve flight paths is not only restricted by conflicts with routes from other London airports but also by a slow and inefficient airspace change&amp;nbsp;process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guidance the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CAA&lt;/span&gt; has drafted defines what will happen in the new process, including each stage a sponsor of an airspace change, such as &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LLA&lt;/span&gt; must complete; the stakeholders we must engage with at each stage and the expectations of that engagement; and how the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CAA&lt;/span&gt; assesses proposed&amp;nbsp;changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;London Luton Airport is submitting a formal response to the consultation. However, we believe it is vital that everyone has the opportunity to contribute to the process of airspace&amp;nbsp;modernisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details of the consultation and how to respond can be found on the &lt;a href="https://consultations.caa.co.uk/policy-development/draft-airspace-design-guidance/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CAA&lt;/span&gt;’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We encourage all interested parties to take part before the deadline.
Whilst we can never eliminate aircraft noise entirely, we always aim to work constructively with local communities and our partners to strike the right balance between minimising the impact of aircraft noise while maximising the positive social and economic benefits of a successful&amp;nbsp;airport. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours&amp;nbsp;sincerely &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neil Thompson
Operations&amp;nbsp;Director&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term='"consultation"'></category><category term='"Politics"'></category><category term='"Knebworth"'></category><category term='"social media"'></category></entry></feed>