<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Steve Hemingway's Blog - "Knebworth"</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/feeds/knebworth.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://stevehemingway.github.io/</id><updated>2018-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Update on the Station Pub</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/update-on-the-station-pub-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2018-09-10:/update-on-the-station-pub-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;The Saga&amp;nbsp;Continues&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next meeting of the Planning Control Committee is due to meet on Thursday 20th Sept to review the reasons for refusal of the applicationto redevelop the station pub (ref.&amp;nbsp;17/01622/1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general idea is to simplify the reasons for refusal to avoid the appeal …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;The Saga&amp;nbsp;Continues&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next meeting of the Planning Control Committee is due to meet on Thursday 20th Sept to review the reasons for refusal of the applicationto redevelop the station pub (ref.&amp;nbsp;17/01622/1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general idea is to simplify the reasons for refusal to avoid the appeal being decided by a public enquiry, a very expensive process for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; and for everyone else.&lt;br&gt;
This is the link to the &lt;a href="https://democracy.north-herts.gov.uk/ieListDocuments.aspx?CId=151&amp;amp;MId=2051&amp;amp;Ver=4#AI2136"&gt;meeting agenda item&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key document is &lt;a href="https://democracy.north-herts.gov.uk/documents/s3114/17016221%20-%20The%20Station%20Inn%20Station%20Approach%20Knebworth%20SG3%206AT.pdf"&gt;the officers&amp;#8217;s report&lt;/a&gt;, which recommends&amp;nbsp;that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reason 1 (loss of pub) is retained, but related to the new version of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NPPF&lt;/span&gt; that is now in force, but a dependence on policy &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ETC7&lt;/span&gt; (change of use of shops etc.) is&amp;nbsp;dropped,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reason 2 (cramped layout) is&amp;nbsp;retained,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reason 3 (inadequate parking) is dropped, on the grounds that Herts Highways had no objection the original&amp;nbsp;application,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reason 4 (noise and odour impacts) is dropped on the grounds that this can be mitigated in&amp;nbsp;practice,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reason 5 (lack of completed S106 Obligation) is dropped on the grounds that it is likely one will be in place by the time the appeal takes&amp;nbsp;place,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where Reason 1 etc. are the reasons originally given by the Planning Control Committee in its decision on 19th April&amp;nbsp;2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a discussion about this &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/StationPubKnebworth/permalink/542004112919167/"&gt;on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SOS&lt;/span&gt; Pub Facebook Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term='"Knebworth"'></category><category term='"North Herts"'></category><category term='"Knebworth"'></category><category term='"community"'></category></entry><entry><title>I am still around but am more active on Twitter nowadaystitle: “A voice from the past”</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/i-am-still-around-but-am-more-active-on-twitter-nowadaystitle-a-voice-from-the-past-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2018-09-06:/i-am-still-around-but-am-more-active-on-twitter-nowadaystitle-a-voice-from-the-past-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;There!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry I haven&amp;#8217;t been posting much. I don&amp;#8217;t go to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; meetings any longer - yay! - and it&amp;#8217;s been the holiday season.
The Parish Council continues, and we are in danger of going up to full strength, which is no mean feat.
Graveley is struggling to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello&amp;nbsp;There!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry I haven&amp;#8217;t been posting much. I don&amp;#8217;t go to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; meetings any longer - yay! - and it&amp;#8217;s been the holiday season.
The Parish Council continues, and we are in danger of going up to full strength, which is no mean feat.
Graveley is struggling to  be quorate, which has required &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; to step in.
Members of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt; regularly discover they have better things to do with their time, so if you fancy serving the community in this capacity, it&amp;#8217;s always worth dropping a note to the Clerk to say that your&amp;#8217;e&amp;nbsp;interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Station Pub is a big issue. The appeal has been submitted and the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SOS&lt;/span&gt; Pub group are busily raising money and instructing experts to back up &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; in its decision to reject the original application. Their Facebook Group has the latest twists in that saga which, unfortunately, might run and&amp;nbsp;run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; members for Knebworth seem both very active on social media, particularly in the area of reporting of missed bins. It has to be said that &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; did not exactly cover itself in glory over letting this new contract, especially as East Herts, which has the same contractor and a very similar service with the exception that it has universal brown bin collection, is experienced no difficulties, as far as I am&amp;nbsp;aware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best&amp;nbsp;Regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve.&amp;nbsp;07712176618.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.twitter.com/SteveKnebworth"&gt;me on&amp;nbsp;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term='"Knebworth"'></category><category term='"North Herts"'></category><category term='"Knebworth"'></category><category term='"community"'></category></entry><entry><title>Hurray, we finally have a working pub in Knebworth - and what a pub!title: “The Lytton Arms Re-opens triumphantly”</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/hurray-we-finally-have-a-working-pub-in-knebworth-and-what-a-pubtitle-the-lytton-arms-re-opens-triumphantly-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2018-05-20:/hurray-we-finally-have-a-working-pub-in-knebworth-and-what-a-pubtitle-the-lytton-arms-re-opens-triumphantly-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had to wait a long time for &lt;a href="http://www.thelyttonarms.co.uk/"&gt;The Lytton Arms&lt;/a&gt; to re-open, but on Thursday the 17th May the day we&amp;#8217;ve all been waiting for arrived. The Lytton Arms was once again open for&amp;nbsp;business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pub has been upgraded in many ways, some visible, some less …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve had to wait a long time for &lt;a href="http://www.thelyttonarms.co.uk/"&gt;The Lytton Arms&lt;/a&gt; to re-open, but on Thursday the 17th May the day we&amp;#8217;ve all been waiting for arrived. The Lytton Arms was once again open for&amp;nbsp;business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pub has been upgraded in many ways, some visible, some less&amp;nbsp;so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the kitchen has been totally refurbished and is now state of the&amp;nbsp;art,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the cellar has been re-fitted and can accommodate nine cask ales and a cask&amp;nbsp;cider,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the old conservatory with the fly-catching nets has gone, and in its place is a modern, warm&amp;nbsp;replacement,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the outside area (where the beer festival casks were set up) is now opened out right through to the boundary with the fields. This is a huge improvement on the old garden, and is perfect for this time of&amp;nbsp;year,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;every square centimetre of paintwork has been renewed, and the colour scheme&amp;nbsp;modernised,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the roof and structural features of the building have all been&amp;nbsp;fixed!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are probably more improvements, but the main thing for me is that the pub now has plenty of beer, quick food service, a 50% discount on food until the end of the month (search for the code, but you&amp;#8217;ll probably get it anyway if you ask), and a marvellous buzz of local residents enjoying a quiet drink in comfortable&amp;nbsp;surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason has now taken over the running of the pub, with a very able team, which includes Stef, who will be familiar to all the regulars from the late James Price&amp;#8217;s time running The Lytton. The pub is now part of &lt;a href="http://www.acinns.co.uk/"&gt;Anglian Country Inns&lt;/a&gt;, a highly professional operation run by Cliff Nye, brother of Steve Nye, former landlord at the&amp;nbsp;pub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current beers include Fat Sprat by Adnams,  Koha by Mad Squirrel, Happy People by Shiny People, Nelson&amp;#8217;s Revenge by Woodfords, Hawse Buckler by Oakham, Bring Me Sunshine by Tring, Lucky Lobster by Brancaster (part of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AC&lt;/span&gt; Inns), Tiki Blonde by Mad Squirrel, Squid Ink by &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XT&lt;/span&gt;, Take 5 by Harpoon and Affligem by De Smelt as well as Rapple, a Raspberry cider by Apple Cottage. However, even as I type this some of these brews will have been replace. It&amp;#8217;s very unlikely you&amp;#8217;ll visit and not find anything interesting to&amp;nbsp;drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lytton now has its own social media presence: on &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/TheLyttonArms/"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/lyttonarms/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheLyttonArms"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Start hitting those &amp;#8216;Follow&amp;#8217; buttons now for the latest&amp;nbsp;offers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term='"Knebworth"'></category><category term='"North Herts"'></category><category term='"Knebworth"'></category><category term='"pubs"'></category><category term='"community"'></category></entry><entry><title>Station Pub</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/station-pub.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-13T14:12:17+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-13T14:12:17+00:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2017-02-13:/station-pub.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;The Station Pub, Knebworth,&amp;nbsp;Campaign&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;comments = true
lang: &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EN&lt;/span&gt;-gb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experience of the Station Pub in Knebworth is not one that makes me want to go back. The pub is cold, noisy and rarely populated by anyone I know. This is a pity, as it&amp;#8217;s a very short distance from where I live. A few months ago, word went out that it had been advertised for sale. There were a few discussions about it in the Parish Council, where we decided that we&amp;#8217;d better apply for it to be listed as an asset of community value. Planning applications to develop a very high density development of flats have been received for the site across the road, which have so far been refused, but eventually will result in some residential development happening. In spite of the fact that this is not something that anyone who lives in the village want to see&amp;nbsp;built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, heard that the pub had closed its doors, and the staff had been redeployed in other Greene King pubs nearby. A flurry of activity happened, which resulted&amp;nbsp;in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a new Twitter account was set up to tweet the latest news about the&amp;nbsp;pub,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a new Facebook being set up that rapidly went from zero to around 600 members by the end of the&amp;nbsp;weekend,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a new website being created, which has received hundreds of&amp;nbsp;hits,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a mailing list being set up to collect pledges and offers to help with a&amp;nbsp;campaign.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the website &lt;a href="https://www.stationpub.org.uk"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, where you&amp;#8217;ll find links to all the aspects of the campaign&amp;#8217;s web&amp;nbsp;presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is quite astonishing is how rapidly the residents of Knebworth could be alerted to the closing of the pub and the existence of a campaign to save it. I have always been an advocate of local politicians using social media, usually in the face of extreme skepticism from the assembled company. Although I&amp;#8217;d like to think that this example would persuade them of the effectiveness of the web, my experience is that people can be very obdurate in their&amp;nbsp;views.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term='"Knebworth"'></category><category term='"twitter"'></category><category term='"local"'></category></entry></feed>