<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Steve Hemingway's Blog - Knebworth_Stuff</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/feeds/knebworth_stuff.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://stevehemingway.github.io/</id><updated>2019-09-15T12:31:44+01:00</updated><entry><title>Last Post</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/last-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-15T12:31:44+01:00</published><updated>2019-09-15T12:31:44+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2019-09-15:/last-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;The Last&amp;nbsp;Post&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am no longer a District councillor. I am no longer updating this blog. I will
post occasionally on Twitter or Reddit. I may use a different platform if I
restart my blog in the future as I would prefer this cloud instance to be dedicated to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;The Last&amp;nbsp;Post&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am no longer a District councillor. I am no longer updating this blog. I will
post occasionally on Twitter or Reddit. I may use a different platform if I
restart my blog in the future as I would prefer this cloud instance to be dedicated to
running an email&amp;nbsp;server.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Knebworth_Stuff"></category></entry><entry><title>Is Twitter the key Social Media Platform?</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/is-twitter-the-key-social-media-platform-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-05T10:13:50+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-05T10:13:50+00:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2017-02-05:/is-twitter-the-key-social-media-platform-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="dquo"&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;Is using Twitter worth&amp;nbsp;it?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;My experience of the&amp;nbsp;Twittersphere&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been on Twitter for a long time. Since 2007. From a time before Stephen Fry discovered the medium, and many years before Donald Trump did so. I&amp;#8217;ve mainly used it passively. I kept my account private, and followed only those authors whose work interested me. A lot of libertarian comment and analysis, some humour, especially the dark side. I have a number of followers, but get virtually no engagement with them. They are either people I follow, and feel that it is only good manners to follow back, or people who somehow have the email address linked to the account in the address book they have handed over to Twitter&amp;nbsp;Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I have never tweeted anything very incendiary, and do not follow anyone I wouldn&amp;#8217;t want my mother to know I was following, I decided that when I was elected I&amp;#8217;d better start a new account for the political me. This happened in 2014, and I&amp;#8217;ve been quietly tweeting since, without much&amp;nbsp;traction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of late I&amp;#8217;ve decided to integrate a bit more automation, using ifttt.com, and simply linking my Twitter account to a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FB&lt;/span&gt; page. I&amp;#8217;d previously auto tweeted from my Tumblr blog, but that never seemed to do any&amp;nbsp;good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, for reasons quite beyond me, my follower numbers seem to be accelerating. The threat to close the Station Pub seems a catalyst. Maybe it&amp;#8217;s just that my odd retweet is enough to create a sustaining wave. I confess to paying a magnificent &amp;pound;10 to promote one tweet, but I don&amp;#8217;t think I&amp;#8217;ll be doing that again in a hurry, as there seems to be no way to localize the audience, in contrast to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FB&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Knebworth_Stuff"></category><category term='"Personal"'></category></entry></feed>