<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Steve Hemingway's Blog - "NHDC"</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/feeds/nhdc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://stevehemingway.github.io/</id><updated>2018-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Community Facilities Capital Grant Fund</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/community-facilities-capital-grant-fund-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2018-04-15:/community-facilities-capital-grant-fund-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;North Hertfordshire District Council (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;) has awarded grant funding of over &amp;pound;240,000 to a number of community buildings across the&amp;nbsp;district.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knebworth Scout and Guide Group was awarded &amp;pound;32,000 for essential maintenance to its circa 1950’s headquarters. The funding will be put towards roofing, paving and drainage …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;North Hertfordshire District Council (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;) has awarded grant funding of over &amp;pound;240,000 to a number of community buildings across the&amp;nbsp;district.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knebworth Scout and Guide Group was awarded &amp;pound;32,000 for essential maintenance to its circa 1950’s headquarters. The funding will be put towards roofing, paving and drainage repairs. It is hoped that further funding will be available from the Knebworth Village Trust, which provides capital grants to organisations which are wholly or mainly for the use of residents of the parish of&amp;nbsp;Knebworth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Community Facilities Capital Grant funds will extend the lifespan of the buildings and will continue to help these facilities remain at the heart of the communities they&amp;nbsp;serve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grant funding follows a commitment made by the Council in 2016 to make &amp;pound;1.2 million available over a four year period to help enhance and sustain community facilities across the&amp;nbsp;District.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other awards went to North Herts Minority Ethnic Forum, which was awarded &amp;pound;50,000 to help build an extension which will be used as a meeting room at their headquarters in Whinbush Road,&amp;nbsp;Hitchin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baldock Arts and Heritage Centre was awarded &amp;pound;50,000 towards the conversion of the Old Fire Station, which is part of their building, into a new heritage&amp;nbsp;area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hitchin Educational Foundation was awarded &amp;pound;50,000 towards the renovation of a derelict Scout hall on land between Bancroft and Grammar School&amp;nbsp;Walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pirton Village Hall was awarded &amp;pound;45,000 to build a multi-purpose room for community groups to&amp;nbsp;use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barkway Village Hall was awarded &amp;pound;15,000 to create a new emergency exit and renovate their kitchen&amp;nbsp;area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further information about the Community Facilities Capital Projects Fund, including how to apply for funding, can be found here: &lt;a href="http://www.north-herts.gov.uk/home/community/grants/community-facilities-capital-projects-fund"&gt;www.north-herts.gov.uk/home/community/grants/community-facilities-capital-projects-fund&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term='"NHDC"'></category><category term='"Grants"'></category></entry><entry><title>Press Release from NHDC re Churchgatetitle: “Churchgate”</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/press-release-from-nhdc-re-churchgatetitle-churchgate-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-31T17:42:37+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-31T17:42:37+00:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2018-01-31:/press-release-from-nhdc-re-churchgatetitle-churchgate-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Councillors to consider potential scheme to regenerate Hitchin’s Churchgate&amp;nbsp;Centre&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new potential joint venture opportunity for the regeneration of the Churchgate Centre in Hitchin will be discussed at a meeting of North Hertfordshire District Council’s (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;) Full Council on 8 February.
The potential joint venture between the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Councillors to consider potential scheme to regenerate Hitchin’s Churchgate&amp;nbsp;Centre&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new potential joint venture opportunity for the regeneration of the Churchgate Centre in Hitchin will be discussed at a meeting of North Hertfordshire District Council’s (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt;) Full Council on 8 February.
The potential joint venture between the Council and Shearer Property Group would see a ‘face-lift’ of the existing shopping centre, improving the quality of the units available and in turn making them more attractive to retailers. The scheme would also see improved public open space and investment in Hitchin’s historic&amp;nbsp;market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the meeting Councillors will be asked to consider supporting the principle of a joint venture regeneration of the Churchgate Centre, with the Council as funder of the regeneration. In return the Council would receive the lion’s share of the ongoing revenue generated. The Shearer Property Group would provide their specialist expertise and knowledge, essential to making a scheme such as this a success. If the principle is supported further detailed work would then be undertaken to ensure the proposals were deliverable, before a final decision is&amp;nbsp;made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Council has been seeking to regenerate this area of Hitchin for many years, however previous potential schemes have come up against a number of challenges, including the size of the scheme, the cost of buying, knocking down and rebuilding the shopping centre and finding a suitable location for the market. It is hoped that the proposal for a smaller regeneration, which does not propose knocking down the Churchgate centre will address many of the previous&amp;nbsp;concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cllr Lynda Needham, Leader of the Council&amp;nbsp;said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased that the regeneration of Churchgate is back on the agenda. The proposals would improve the retail offer in Hitchin, bring much needed investment to Hitchin Market and make the surrounding area more attractive, as well as provide an investment opportunity for the&amp;nbsp;Council.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that the people of Hitchin are keen to see a suitable proposal come forward for the area and we look forward to debating this potential joint venture opportunity on 8&amp;nbsp;February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term='"NHDC"'></category><category term='"Politics"'></category><category term='"North Herts"'></category></entry></feed>