<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Steve Hemingway's Blog - "Planning", "NHDC"</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/feeds/planning-nhdc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://stevehemingway.github.io/</id><updated>2018-04-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>No, I did not vote to develop sites around Knebworthtitle: “No, I did not vote to develop sites around Knebworth”</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/no-i-did-not-vote-to-develop-sites-around-knebworthtitle-no-i-did-not-vote-to-develop-sites-around-knebworth-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2018-04-30:/no-i-did-not-vote-to-develop-sites-around-knebworthtitle-no-i-did-not-vote-to-develop-sites-around-knebworth-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;TL&lt;/span&gt;;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DR&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Council Meeting of 11th April 2017 I voted to save  public consultation responses from the shredder. My political opponents are painting this as if I voted to build on fields all around Knebworth. As I have repeatedly said in the past, I am opposed to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;TL&lt;/span&gt;;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DR&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; Council Meeting of 11th April 2017 I voted to save  public consultation responses from the shredder. My political opponents are painting this as if I voted to build on fields all around Knebworth. As I have repeatedly said in the past, I am opposed to all Green Belt development around the&amp;nbsp;village.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The actual resolutions I voted&amp;nbsp;for:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have had a number of local residents contacting me stating that I voted for development to take place on sites around Knebworth. This is simply untrue.  In the meeting of the full Council on 11th April 2017, I voted for the following&amp;nbsp;motion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1) That the results of the Proposed Submission consultation, as set out in the Regulation 22 Consultation Statement attached as Appendix 1 to the report, be noted and&amp;nbsp;recorded;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(2) That the new Local Plan for North Hertfordshire, attached as Appendix 2 to the report, together with the Schedule of Proposed Additional Modifications attached as Appendix 3, and other associated documentation, be approved and submitted for examination by the Secretary of&amp;nbsp;State;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(3) That the revised Local Development Scheme for North Hertfordshire, attached as Appendix 4 to the report, be approved with effect from 12 April&amp;nbsp;2017;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(4) That delegated powers be granted to the Head of Development and Building Control, in consultation with the Executive Member for Planning and Enterprise, to produce such additional documentation as is required (including documentation requested by the appointed Inspector and the proposing of main modifications) before and during the examination of the Local Plan;&amp;nbsp;and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(5) That Officers continue to regularly update Members on the progress of the Examination through the Strategic Planning Matters reports which are submitted to&amp;nbsp;Cabinet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;REASON&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FOR&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DECISION&lt;/span&gt;: To ensure that North Hertfordshire continues to progress a new Local Plan for the management of development in the&amp;nbsp;District.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further details of the meeting, including Appendix 1 mentioned in the resolution may be read on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; website &lt;a href="https://democracy.north-herts.gov.uk/CeListDocuments.aspx?CommitteeId=136&amp;amp;MeetingId=519&amp;amp;DF=11%2f04%2f2017&amp;amp;Ver=2"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This motion is purely about allowing the public consultation that took place in late 2016 to be examined. This is not about the Council ignoring this consultation: under the very rigidly defined process for producing a Local Plan, &lt;strong&gt;responses to the consultation on the Draft Plan are examined by a Planning Inspector on behalf of the Secretary of State&lt;/strong&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no possibility of me voting to approve the Local Plan. Members of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NHDC&lt;/span&gt; do not have the power to do this. This power is vested in the Secretary of State for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DCLG&lt;/span&gt;.  The Examination in Public finished last month, and the Inspector will use this as the basis on which to write his Report, which will be submitted to the Secretary of State for adoption. This may happen in 2019, at the&amp;nbsp;earliest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I have written before, the Local Plan does not give permission for the development of any sites around Knebworth. Before any sites on the periphery of the village are developed they will have to obtain full planning permission which will include the normal consultation process that is required before planning permission is granted. This will be withheld unless applicants can demonstrate that access and supporting infrastructure are&amp;nbsp;adequate.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term='"Planning", "NHDC"'></category><category term='"Planning"'></category><category term='"North Herts"'></category><category term='"Voting"'></category></entry><entry><title>EiP - Local Plan Examination. End of Public Hearings</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/eip-local-plan-examination-end-of-public-hearings-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2018-04-15:/eip-local-plan-examination-end-of-public-hearings-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the end of the hearing sessions on 27 March the Inspector set out the next steps in the EiP of the Local Plan. A note has now been prepared and this can be viewed in the examination documents &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ED130&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the hearing sessions the Inspector asked the Council to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the end of the hearing sessions on 27 March the Inspector set out the next steps in the EiP of the Local Plan. A note has now been prepared and this can be viewed in the examination documents &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ED130&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the hearing sessions the Inspector asked the Council to complete a
number of actions to provide additional information to the
examination. Some of these actions have already been completed
and the Council are intending to finish the remainder by the end of&amp;nbsp;April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actions and the completed responses, as they become
available, can all be viewed on the website through the following link: &lt;a href="https://www.north-herts.gov.uk/planning/planning-policy/localplan/local-plan-examination/examination-actions"&gt;www.north-herts.gov.uk/planning/planning-policy/localplan/local-plan-examination/examination-actions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Inspector has all the documents arising out of the actions he will take
a view on whether he requires any further information on any of the
matters examined during the hearing&amp;nbsp;sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where representors have not yet had the opportunity to provide
written comments on documents provided by the Council, he will be
inviting them to do so in May. As with hearing statements,
representors will only be able to comment on documents that are
relevant to the issues raised in their regulation 19 responses. The
Programme Officer will contact all regulation 19 respondents in May
to notify them of the details and deadline for the provision of&amp;nbsp;comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Inspector will then invite the Council to respond to these.
The timetable for the proposed main modifications cannot be
defined at this stage, but they will be subject to the normal six
week consultation period. Following this my report will be sent to
the Council to allow it to check the main modifications for factual&amp;nbsp;accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term='"Planning", "NHDC"'></category><category term='"Politics"'></category><category term='"North Herts"'></category><category term='"Planning"'></category></entry></feed>