<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Steve Hemingway's Blog - "politics","local plan"</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/feeds/politicslocal-plan.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://stevehemingway.github.io/</id><updated>2017-04-06T09:42:12+01:00</updated><entry><title>Toeing the Party Line</title><link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/toeing-the-party-line-EN-gb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-06T09:42:12+01:00</published><updated>2017-04-06T09:42:12+01:00</updated><author><name>stevehemingway</name></author><id>tag:stevehemingway.github.io,2017-04-06:/toeing-the-party-line-EN-gb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The following letter appeared in the various North Herts editions of today&amp;#8217;s Comet newspaper.
You can access the &amp;#8216;e-edition&amp;#8217; (with some difficulty) via &lt;a href="http://www.thecomet.net/home/e-edition"&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;Sir,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to the &amp;#8216;anonymous&amp;#8217; (why?) correspondent who stated that the
Conservative Group has adopted rules regarding voting. I am sure they …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The following letter appeared in the various North Herts editions of today&amp;#8217;s Comet newspaper.
You can access the &amp;#8216;e-edition&amp;#8217; (with some difficulty) via &lt;a href="http://www.thecomet.net/home/e-edition"&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear&amp;nbsp;Sir,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to the &amp;#8216;anonymous&amp;#8217; (why?) correspondent who stated that the
Conservative Group has adopted rules regarding voting. I am sure they are
aware that all Parties, including the Liberal Democrats, have rules in place
that require members to support agreed Party positions. They are completely
incorrect in saying that anyone voting &amp;#8220;in support of their residents&amp;#8221; will
be immediately subject to a three month suspension. In fact, local
Conservative Party rules contain provisions allowing members to vote against
or abstain on the agreed Party position when the matter specifically affects
their ward or is a matter of conscience. An examination of the recorded vote
on the Local Plan in September will confirm that there were several
Conservative members who did not support the proposals at that time.
The North Herts Conservative Party’s agreed position continues to be that
this Plan should be supported, as a whole, as this is the only way in which
we can protect our District from completely unchecked development. The Party
Whip works closely with all Conservative members who may wish to abstain or
vote against that position to ensure their reasons continue to fall within
the rules of the Party. An approach not dissimilar to Liberal Democrat and
Labour Party led&amp;nbsp;authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A perhaps more interesting question is exactly what detailed research your
correspondent has done in believing that the &amp;#8216;wishes of the residents&amp;#8217; are
to vote against the Local Plan? There are approximately 131,000 residents in
North Hertfordshire and we have received 5,675 representations on the Local
Plan. Similarly, your correspondent focuses only on the &amp;#8216;residents who voted
him/her in as a councillor&amp;#8217;. North Herts Conservatives work for every single
resident in North Hertfordshire, not just the approximately  75% that vote
or the ~1% who object, but the 100% who will be affected by unrestricted and
unchecked housing&amp;nbsp;development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://web.north-herts.gov.uk/aksnherts/users/public/admin/main.pl?op=MemberDetails&amp;amp;keyid=92"&gt;Cllr. Julian Cunningham&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term='"politics","local plan"'></category><category term='"Politics"'></category><category term='"Knebworth"Description: "Letter from NHDC Concservatives Group Whip'></category><category term='Cllr. Julian Cunningham"'></category></entry></feed>