<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Steve Hemingway&#39;s website</title>
    <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Steve Hemingway&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>(c) Steve Hemingway 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 15:33:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stevehemingway.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>KCC Christmas Concert</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/2018/kcc_christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 15:33:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/2018/kcc_christmas/</guid>
      <description>Everyone enjoyed himself at the wonderful concert laid on by Knebworth Community Chorus this Saturday. The Village Hall was full to bursting, and many mince pies were consumed. A fair volume of mulled wine was drunk too.
The children of St Michael&amp;rsquo;s, Woolmer Green School put on a wonderful performance of singing and playing their instruments: violins and flutes.
Merry Christmas!
Steve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Main Modifications NHDC Local Plan</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/main_mods/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 21:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/main_mods/</guid>
      <description>Mods which relate to Knebworth MM 283 - MM 296 are the relevant paragraphs. The Main Modifications will be considered by the Council&amp;rsquo;s Cabinet at a special meeting on Monday 10 December 2018.
Subject to their approval, consultation will then be held on the Main Modifications. This consultation will also provide the opportunity to comment on the additional work produced by the Council following the hearing sessions. Details of the consultation will be published on the NHDC website following the Cabinet meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-emptive copyright filter</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/pre-emptive-copyright-filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/pre-emptive-copyright-filter/</guid>
      <description>The European Parliament voted to burden every blog like this with an obligation to anticipate any possible copyright breach, even to the point of using the title of a title elsewhere. To my mind politicians do not understand the Internet and instinctively do the wrong thing.
This is what the EFF has to say:
 Despite waves of calls and emails from European Internet users, the European Parliament today voted to accept the principle of a universal pre-emptive copyright filter for content-sharing sites, as well as the idea that news publishers should have the right to sue others for quoting news items online or even using their titles as links to articles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on the Station Pub</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/station_pub_revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/station_pub_revisited/</guid>
      <description>The Saga Continues The next meeting of the Planning Control Committee is due to meet on Thursday 20th Sept to review the reasons for refusal of the applicationto redevelop the station pub (ref. 17/01622/1).
The general idea is to simplify the reasons for refusal to avoid the appeal being decided by a public enquiry, a very expensive process for NHDC and for everyone else.
This is the link to the meeting agenda item.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A voice from the past</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/hello_from_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/hello_from_me/</guid>
      <description>Hello There!
Sorry I haven&amp;rsquo;t been posting much. I don&amp;rsquo;t go to NHDC meetings any longer - yay! - and it&amp;rsquo;s been the holiday season. The Parish Council continues, and we are in danger of going up to full strength, which is no mean feat. Graveley is struggling to be quorate, which has required NHDC to step in. Members of the PC regularly discover they have better things to do with their time, so if you fancy serving the community in this capacity, it&amp;rsquo;s always worth dropping a note to the Clerk to say that your&amp;rsquo;e interested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lytton Arms Re-opens triumphantly</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/thelyttonarms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/thelyttonarms/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve had to wait a long time for The Lytton Arms to re-open, but on Thursday the 17th May the day we&amp;rsquo;ve all been waiting for arrived. The Lytton Arms was once again open for business.
The pub has been upgraded in many ways, some visible, some less so:
 the kitchen has been totally refurbished and is now state of the art, the cellar has been re-fitted and can accommodate nine cask ales and a cask cider, the old conservatory with the fly-catching nets has gone, and in its place is a modern, warm replacement, the outside area (where the beer festival casks were set up) is now opened out right through to the boundary with the fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>District Council Elections</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/election_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/election_2018/</guid>
      <description>Update on election from 3 May Knebworth Ward has fallen to the Lib Dems in spite of all the hard work put in by my supporters and me. A very intensive campaign from the Lib Dems paid off with a victory for first time candidate Lisa Nash. The full results were as follows:
   Name of Candidate Political Party Votes cast Elected?     Steve HEMINGWAY Conservative Party 742 N   Klazina HOFMANN Labour Party 141 N   Lisa NASH Liberal Democrats 957 Y   Nick NEWSON Green Party 29 N    Electorate: 3992 | Ballot papers counted:1876 | Ballot papers rejected:0 | Turnout: 46.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No, I did not vote to develop sites around Knebworth</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/local_plan_vote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/local_plan_vote/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: In the NHDC Council Meeting of 11th April 2017 I voted to save public consultation responses from the shredder. My political opponents are painting this as if I voted to build on fields all around Knebworth. As I have repeatedly said in the past, I am opposed to all Green Belt development around the village.
The actual resolutions I voted for: I have had a number of local residents contacting me stating that I voted for development to take place on sites around Knebworth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herts County Council is consulting on the proposed additional double yellow lines in Gun Lane and Park Lane.</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/dyls_in_park_lane_gun_lane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 17:42:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/dyls_in_park_lane_gun_lane/</guid>
      <description>Herts County Council is consulting on the proposed additional double yellow lines in Gun Lane and Park Lane.
Objections to the proposals should be made in writing to Terry Curtis, Postal Point (CH0242) First Floor, East Link Corridor, County Hall, Pegs Lane, Hertford SG13 8DN or tro.team@hertfordshire.gov.uk by 26 April 2018.
You can comment via the website at https://www.hertfordshire.gov.uk/services/highways-roads-and-pavements/changes-to-your-road/traffic-regulation-orders/traffic-regulation-orders.aspx (search for &amp;ldquo;NH00618&amp;rdquo; on the page).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Facilities Capital Grant Fund</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/cfcgf_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/cfcgf_2018/</guid>
      <description>North Hertfordshire District Council (NHDC) has awarded grant funding of over &amp;pound;240,000 to a number of community buildings across the district.
Knebworth Scout and Guide Group was awarded &amp;pound;32,000 for essential maintenance to its circa 1950’s headquarters. The funding will be put towards roofing, paving and drainage repairs. It is hoped that further funding will be available from the Knebworth Village Trust, which provides capital grants to organisations which are wholly or mainly for the use of residents of the parish of Knebworth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EiP - Local Plan Examination. End of Public Hearings</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/inspectors_note_eip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/inspectors_note_eip/</guid>
      <description>At the end of the hearing sessions on 27 March the Inspector set out the next steps in the EiP of the Local Plan. A note has now been prepared and this can be viewed in the examination documents ED130.
During the hearing sessions the Inspector asked the Council to complete a number of actions to provide additional information to the examination. Some of these actions have already been completed and the Council are intending to finish the remainder by the end of April.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Southern Rural grant funding available for 2018/19</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/carry-over-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/carry-over-budget/</guid>
      <description>As a result of the decision not to cease Area Committee Grants in the February Council Meeting when the Revenue Budget was agreed, residents of North Herts once again have the opportunity to apply for grants from Area Committees.
If you are a local charity, voluntary group or not for profit organisation you are eligible for a share of its almost &amp;pound;90,000 grant funding pot in 2018-19.
The Council provides grants to voluntary groups and not-for-profits through its five Area Committees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is responsible for controlling verge parking?</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/verge-parking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/verge-parking/</guid>
      <description>Over our long, wet winter in our congested village with its inadequate parking facilities, one issue comes up time and time again. This is the anti-social habit of drivers parking with one (or more) pairs of wheels on the grass verge, turning it into a muddy wreck.
The solution is to contact:
 HCC – Herts Highways are responsible for putting bollards on grass verges as these areas are part of the highway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Officer&#39;s Report for Station Pub Application</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/station_pub_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/station_pub_report/</guid>
      <description>Date of expiry of statutory period: 26.09.2017
Submitted Plan Nos
SE-760-01 SE-760-03 SE-760-02 SE-760-20C SE-760-21B SE-760-22A SE-760-23A SE-760-24A 6098-1 SE-760-25C SE-760 revA
1.0Site History
1.1There is no relevant site history.
2.0Policies
2.1North Hertfordshire District Local Plan No. 2 with Alterations (Saved Policies)
Policy 5 – Excluded Villages
Policy 26 – Housing Proposals
Policy 51 – Development Effects and Planning Gain
Policy 57 – Residential Guidelines and Standards
Supplementary Planning Documents</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knebworth JMI Environmental Area</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/knebworth_jmi_environmental_area/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 17:42:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/knebworth_jmi_environmental_area/</guid>
      <description>The Environmental Area, AKA the Wildlife Haven It was fascinating to see the Knebworth Primary School Environmental Area when I visited the school on Friday, 31st March for the official opening, with Stephen McPartland MP. I have never really ventured very far beyond the dining room in the school (where Knebworth Village Trust meetings are held).
Now, thanks to many weeks of hard work put in by Alena Evans of Evans on Earth the EA is finished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregates Yard Planning Application</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/chas_lowe_sandyard_application/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/chas_lowe_sandyard_application/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I spoke at a Planning Control Committee meeting. I was supporting the Parish Council, in the form of Cllr Roger Willcocks, in objecting to application, &amp;lsquo;17/02652/1 - 135A LONDON ROAD, KNEBWORTH, SG3 6EX&amp;rsquo;. This is the conversion of the old aggregates yard, part of Chas Lowe &amp;amp; Sons, into two 2-bed flats and two commercial (retail) units. The grounds on which we objected were principally to do with parking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NORTH HERTFORDSHIRE DISTRICT COUNCIL – MARCH UPDATE</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/march_update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/march_update/</guid>
      <description>Station Pub Planning Application (Ref 17/01622/1) It was good to see the support at the Pop Up Pub in the village hall last month, held as part of the SOSPUB Campaign (see photo). The planning application for the Station Pub, which retains a pub but includes development of part of the site into flats, is still to come before the NHDC Planning Control Committee, this month’s meeting is on Thursday 15th March, 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Do I Call When I Want to Call The Council?</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/who_do_i_call/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 17:03:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/who_do_i_call/</guid>
      <description>North Herts District Council Tel: 01462-474000 Email: service@north-herts.gov.uk Twitter: @NorthHertsDC
Web: www.north-herts.gov.uk
Contact NHDC about all the following:
 Vandalism Noise Bonfires and Construction Dust Licensed Premises Stray Dogs Public Toilets (not in villages) Abandoned or burned-out vehicles Dog Fouling issues Council Tax/Housing Benefit NHDC Housing (for the following:)  Actual or threatened homelessness Housing debt advice Advice on any housing issue Common Housing Register queries   NHDC are responsible for parks and gardens in the towns in the District, but for these, call the contractor directly:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Churchgate</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/churchgate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 17:42:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/churchgate/</guid>
      <description>Councillors to consider potential scheme to regenerate Hitchin’s Churchgate Centre A new potential joint venture opportunity for the regeneration of the Churchgate Centre in Hitchin will be discussed at a meeting of North Hertfordshire District Council’s (NHDC) Full Council on 8 February. The potential joint venture between the Council and Shearer Property Group would see a ‘face-lift’ of the existing shopping centre, improving the quality of the units available and in turn making them more attractive to retailers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Twitter the key Social Media Platform?</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.com/posts/twitter/</guid>
      <description>My experience of the Twittersphere I&amp;rsquo;ve been on Twitter for a long time. Since 2007. From a time before Stephen Fry discovered the medium, and many years before Donald Trump did so. I&amp;rsquo;ve mainly used it passively. I kept my account private, and followed only those authors whose work interested me. A lot of libertarian comment and analysis, some humour, especially the dark side. I have a number of followers, but get virtually no engagement with them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>