<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on Steve Hemingway</title>
    <link>https://stevehemingway.github.io/tags/development/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Steve Hemingway</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <atom:link href="https://stevehemingway.github.io/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on Blog Setup</title>
      <link>https://stevehemingway.github.io/posts/update_on_blog_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 15:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevehemingway.github.io/posts/update_on_blog_setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Git submodules are still a bit of a mystery to me, but I yet again followed the instructions on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; and this time it kind of worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It finally dawned on me that git push and pull link a local work tree to a remote repository. You can&amp;rsquo;t run a web server on the remote machine, point it at the repository, and expect it to serve web pages, even though that&amp;rsquo;s what the repository (possibly) contains. Git gurus, stop rolling your eyes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t even checkout the repository on the local machine because then git push will complain that you&amp;rsquo;re pushing to a master branch that it active and checked out on the remote machine. I discovered that the hard way. My web server does run a git server process. I tried it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, after a bit of faffing around (!) I decided to edit the hugo source web file source on my local machine (running msys2 under Windows), push to github.com (because it is so awesome as a git server, and its free), then git pull the (built) website source from github to my web server directory on my dreamhost shared web server machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to add to my blog I create a markdown file, add it to the github pages repo, then git pull it to the dreamhost machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a slight added complication, I run the DNS for this domain on another machine - a digital ocean dropbox, running mail-in-a-box. I discover I have to look in the dreamhost control panel DNS settings for the domain to see what IP address to use for the A record. I can&amp;rsquo;t just use the main (arago) IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who would have thought that something so simple could be so &amp;hellip;. messy?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>